You got any stories, friend?
Yeah, I suppose I do.
You want to know the
saddest thing I ever saw?
When I was a boy, my
brother and I wanted a dog.
So, our father took
in an old greyhound.
- Never seen a greyhound, have you?
- No.
Seen a few showdowns in my day.
A greyhound is a racing dog.
It spends its life
running in circles,
chasing a bit of felt
made up like a rabbit.
One day, we took it to the park.
Now, Dad had warned
us how fast that dog was,
but we couldn't resist.
So, my brother
took off the leash.
And in that instant,
the dog spotted a cat.
I imagine it must have looked
just like that piece of felt.
He ran.
Never saw a thing as
beautiful as that old dog running.
Until at last, he
finally caught it.
And to the horror of
everyone, he killed that little cat.
Tore it to pieces.
Then he just sat
there, confused.
That dog had spent its whole
life trying to catch that thing.
Now it had no idea what to do.
That is one humdinger
of a story, partner.
Shall we drink to the
lady with the white shoes?
Find me.
Show me how.
There she is. Pariah.
City of outcasts, delinquents,
thieves, whores, and murderers.
Once we cross the gates,
you will reap the full benefits of El
Lazo's gratitude for my safe return.
Are you all right?
Of course.
Did I do something wrong?
Just earlier, I thought I
heard you talking to someone.
Must have been the wind.
Come on.
This way.
The farther up we
get from Sweetwater,
the more grandiose, the
bigger the narratives become.
It's beautiful in its own way.
For once, I agree.
Some of the park feels like it
was designed by committee,
market-tested, but everything
out here is more raw.
But it doesn't come cheap.
Rumor is, they are
hemorrhaging cash.
We're considering
buying them out.
Supposedly, this place was
all started by a partnership,
and then right before the park
opened, one of the partners killed himself.
It sent the park
into a free fall.
I mean, I don't know any of the
details. I don't even know his name.
You must have a team of
lawyers looking at this place.
Yeah, well, they came up empty.
He's a complete mystery.
Not even a picture.
Well, whoever
designed this place,
you get the feeling they don't
think very much of people.
Who are they?
They call themselves
the Army of New Virginia.
Everyone else calls
them the Confederados.
My father told me about them.
Ex-Confederate soldiers that
refused to surrender after the war.
Now they work as
mercenaries below the border.
They are the key to this game.
What game?
The biggest game there is.
War.
Supposedly, it's at the
far reaches of the park.
Now, I've never made it that
far, but this could be our chance.
I've known plenty of truly
fucked-up individuals in my time.
Few that'd hold a candle
to you, sure. But this one?
Theodore Flood?
He was Wyatt's friend.
You know, his former associations
are exactly why we need him.
He's gonna lead me
straight to the big bad wolf.
I wouldn't count on that.
Aw, shit.
Didn't take you for
the charitable type.
You should have left
him on that tree to die.
You believe in fate, Lawrence?
If the bitch exists,
I'd like to kick her in
the teeth about now.
Don't be so glib.
You'll hurt my feelings.
As another old friend
of mine likes to say,
"There's a path for everyone.
Your path leads you back to me."
Do you ever wonder why I've
kept you with me this whole journey?
Maybe you like the pleasure of
my company, you sadistic fuck.
Maybe I do.
There's not a man in the world who
would take the tone with me you do.
In a past life, perhaps.
Teddy here is not
looking long for this world.
Nearest healer is in Pariah.
But ain't no way he's
gonna make it that far.
He's lost too much blood.
Are you lost?
Our friend here is a
little worse for the wear.
Any water nearby, son?
There's a creek on the
other side of the canyon.
Fetch us some, would you?
Now, hurry.
Our friend here needs
some if he's going to make it.
Get.
Eh.
Too small.
What does that mean?
And what are you
sending him for water for?
I'm the one you made fill up
the sow's bag this morning.
A shame, really.
I always enjoy our
time together, Lawrence.
What the fuck is that
supposed to mean?
It means I was wrong.
The path that brought
you here, it wasn't for me.
It was for him.
Sorry, Lawrence. Guess
I'll see you on the other side.
Uh-oh.
Not looking good for you.
Closing.
Forget it. I win.
I always win!
Not fair.
All you had was a smashed
cheekbone and an ear.
You know how hard it is to get
the auricle curves symmetrical?
You had to, what, plug and
patch a couple bullet holes?
And a knife wound.
It was a contained incision.
Almost like they were
looking for something.
Are you fucking kidding me?
You really think this little fuck
puppet's coming to get you? Huh?
It got off the table and ran.
That's 'cause you forgot
to put her in sleep mode.
Yeah, I really think I
remembered to put her in sleep.
You know, that's the
thing about forgetting.
You think you
remembered, but you didn't.
- Break time.
- Yeah!
I've got a ham sandwich
and a nubile redhead
loaded up in the VR tank,
awaiting instruction.
Yeah.
Welcome back.
Looks like a couple gallons of Lawrence
swirling around in you did you good.
Ready to get back on the road?
Merciful thing would
be to put a bullet in me.
Whoever said I was merciful?
And it's not my
fault you're suffering.
You used to be beautiful.
When this place started, I
opened one of you up once.
Million little perfect pieces.
And then they changed you.
Made you this sad, real mess.
Flesh and bone, just like us.
They said it would
improve the park experience.
But you know why
they really did it?
It was cheaper.
Your humanity is cost-effective.
So was your suffering.
Whatever it is you
want from me, mister,
I ain't gonna be worth
a damn to you like this.
Well, that would
be a shame, Teddy.
After your misadventure,
Wyatt killed a settler family.
Made off with their daughter.
Girl, I think you know,
name of Dolores.
They have Dolores?
There it is.
The magic word. Come on.
Hey! Much obliged there, son.
Don't worry about him.
Someone'll be
along for him shortly.
Mommy!
Are you all right?
When I ran from home, I
told myself it was the only way.
Lately, I've wondered if in every
moment there aren't many paths.
Choices.
Hanging in the air like ghosts.
And if you could just see them,
you could change your whole life.
Is that what you want? You
want to change your life?
Doesn't everybody want that?
I guess they do.
Maybe that's why they come here.
Whoever you were
before doesn't matter here.
There's no rules
or restrictions.
You can change the story of your
life. You can become someone else.
No one will judge you. No one
in the real world will even know.
The only thing holding
you back is yourself.
What do you mean by that?
You said, "No one in
the real world will know."
I thought you weren't supposed
to notice things like that.
Why wouldn't I?
Recently, it seems
like the whole world
is calling to me in a
way it hasn't before.
Billy, where the hell
have you been? Come on.
El Lazo's agreed to have an
audience with y'all tomorrow.
In the meantime, there's
a brothel I recommend.
Ooh. They have a contortionist.
Oh, I don't think Dolores
would find that very interesting.
Who the fuck cares
what Dolores wants?
She's a goddamn doll!
Can you not say that around her?
I swear, I feel like
she understands.
Of course you do.
May you rest in a deep
and dreamless slumber.
Hello, Dolores.
Do you know where you are?
- I'm in a dream.
- Yes, Dolores.
You're in my dream.
Tell me, do you know
what this dream means?
Dreams are the mind
telling stories to itself.
They don't mean anything.
No. Dreams mean everything.
They are the stories we tell
ourselves of what could be,
who we could become.
Have you been
dreaming again, Dolores?
Imagining yourself breaking
out of your modest little loop?
Taking on a bigger role?
Well, I suppose I can't
begrudge you that.
My father told me to be
satisfied with my lot in life.
That the world owed me nothing.
And so, I made my own world.
Tell me, Dolores,
do you remember
the man I used to be?
I'm sorry.
I'm forgetful, sometimes.
Hardly your fault.
But I'm sure you remember him.
Arnold.
The person who created you.
I'm sorry.
I don't think I recall
anyone by that name.
And yet, you can.
Somewhere, under all
those updates, he is still there.
Perfectly preserved.
Your mind is a walled garden.
Even death cannot touch
the flowers blooming there.
Have you been hearing voices? Has
Arnold been speaking to you again?
No.
You're...
You're hurting me.
Analysis.
When was your last
contact with Arnold?
Last contact, 34 years,
42 days, seven hours ago.
Yes, Dolores.
The day Arnold died.
And you have no records of
any contact with him since?
No.
What was the last
thing he said to you?
He told me I was
going to help him.
Help him do what?
To destroy this place.
But you didn't, did you?
You've been content
in your little loop.
For the most part.
I wonder...
If you did take on that
bigger role for yourself,
would you have been
the hero or the villain?
That's enough, Dolores.
I'm sorry for bothering you,
but there's no one
else left who was there.
No one who understands,
as we understand.
Are we very old friends?
No.
I wouldn't say
"friends," Dolores.
I wouldn't say that at all.
He doesn't know.
I didn't tell him anything.
That's it.
Come on, little one.
Come on.
Oh.
What the fuck?
Grab it!
Ah! God!
Damn it, you little shit!
Jesus! Tell me
you're not this stupid.
You stole a bird and a
fucking behavior tablet?
I wasn't stealing.
I was borrowing.
I haven't got the code
right yet, but with practice...
Whoa, whoa. Whoa.
Is that your ace plan?
You're gonna fix up a birdie
and get yourself a promotion?
You're not a
fucking ornithologist.
And you're sure
as hell not a coder.
You are a butcher.
That is all you will ever be.
So, unless you wanna score
yourself a one-way ticket out of here
for misappropriating
corporate property...
You better destroy
that fucking shit.
Now, come on, we
got another body.
What?
It's her.
Again.
Jesus.
How the hell did you get this job if
you're scared shitless of these things?
Personality testing should have
weeded you out in the embryo.
Now, come on, let's get
this thing back in rotation.
Yesterday you
seemed out of sorts.
Feeling better this morning?
I had troubled dreams.
But I feel more myself now.
Guys, come on.
El Lazo awaits.
I present to you El Lazo.
You're a hard man to find.
Most wanted men are.
We saved your man, Slim,
here, from quite a predicament.
In recompense,
I'd like an introduction to
your Confederado friends.
It's only fair.
There's no such
thing as "fair" here.
In Pariah, justice
ain't just blind,
she's crooked.
Bitch's scales
are always tipped.
If you don't see how,
well, that's 'cause
they're tipped against you.
Still, by way of gratitude,
I can supply you a night with
some very amenable women.
I've fucked enough whores.
You're gonna need
to sweeten the pot.
How about I sweeten
it by killing you quickly?
There's something
you're seeking, isn't there?
I know what that feels like.
I'm seeking something, too.
If you let us, I know
we can help you.
How is it the lunatics
always find their way to me?
Then again, the Confederados are missing
a few bullets in their barrels, too.
You folks just might get along.
A Union convoy is transporting a shipment
of nitroglycerin from the front today.
The Confederados would like
to divest them of said shipment,
but we are not welcome
that side of the border.
A trio of travelers such
as yourselves, however...
You want us to help the
Confederados steal from the Union?
They're just going
to use that nitro
to slaughter your
people below the border.
Personal grudges hold no
sway where profit is concerned.
Oh, we understand.
We're businessmen, too.
Very well, then.
But blondie here, she's gonna need
a change of clothes for the occasion.
Mmm.
My, my, look who's packing.
I don't aim to use this.
Those men are Union
soldiers, like my father was.
I know. We won't hurt them.
We're gonna stick to the plan.
We'll take the nitro and go.
All right.
It's showtime.
Halt!
Howdy.
My associates and I are
here to relieve you of your ride.
Someone's been telling you boys
tales. Nothing in this wagon worth taking.
The story I heard
is one bullet from us,
and that "nothing" blows
you all to kingdom come.
Well, then you understand
why we cannot surrender it.
We're sworn to protect the
people of this young republic
from reckless,
halfwits like you.
Call me halfwit again.
Please.
Do as he says. We
don't want to hurt you.
Yeah, I'd listen to her.
He'll shoot just to
see the fireworks.
Hand them over.
Come on.
Hey. Come on down, give
me your guns. Everybody lives.
Nice and easy.
Right over here. A
little further, please.
Much obliged.
Here you go.
That's for lying.
Stop!
And that was for "halfwit."
And this...
No!
Stop! Please!
Whoo!
That's the spirit!
I knew you would
get into this place.
Yes!
Yup.
Not bad for a day's work.
Vámonos.
We told them
everyone would live.
Guys, looks like
Slim didn't make it.
Whoa.
They put up a fight.
We made them pay for it, though.
Price of doing
business. Slim knew that.
Had my doubts, El Lazo.
But you came through.
We're gonna blow these cactus-eaters
back to the dirt holes they crawled from.
Let's get it down
to the station.
No time to waste.
If I may, Captain,
your men are weary,
with a long road ahead.
You have secured a great
victory for your cause today.
Perhaps an evening of
celebration is in order.
Anything you desire.
What do you say, Captain?
There's another
train in the morning.
You will be a true
asset to our ranks.
All right, Bart.
Let's try this again.
God damn it, man.
You're still miscalibrating by
four centimeters to the right.
You keep pouring
whiskey on the guests,
I'm gonna have to
reassign you to a narrative
where your talents will
go tragically unappreciated.
Hey, that's the host
that tried to kill me.
- Where are you taking that?
- Livestock.
And then the incinerator.
Fuck this.
Fuck.
Isn't she from Behavior?
You think they found something?
- All right. Be cool, dickhead.
- Okay.
No one's looking at us.
Hi.
You're Destin, right?
That's correct.
I almost didn't recognize
you with your pants on. Here.
What the fuck?
There's a common misconception
that the hosts don't log sexual encounters
when they're underground
for reprocessing.
But, like I said, misconception.
Oh, fuck.
I need something.
QA sent a body down here,
the woodcutter from Sector 14.
- I want to see it.
- No.
I can't.
I need this job.
Look, Destin,
in a second, I'm
gonna walk out of here,
and your friends are going to
wonder what this was all about.
Now, your answer can either be,
"I'm helping Behavior track a problem,"
or, "I'm a creepy necro-perv."
Up to you.
Five minutes, then it's
going in the incinerator.
Huh. You took a little more time than
that for your examination, didn't you?
All right, big guy.
What were you doing up there?
What the fuck?
You've been holding
out on me, Maurice.
Oh, shit.
We've got a big problem.
Turns out our big, dumb
friend had some hidden depths.
That is a laser-based
satellite uplink.
This was in the
body of the host?
Mmm-hmm. You were right.
Orion's Belt has three stars, not four.
Our friend wasn't drawing
stars. He was drawing a target.
Someone has been using our
host to smuggle data out of the park.
Now this... This I
could get used to.
You're not going to indulge?
My flesh has tasted a greater
pleasure than any offered here.
War.
It's that good, huh?
Another round? On the house.
There's a place in glory for a
brown man who knows his rank.
You're two able-bodied
men of strong stock.
The road to glory could use more warriors
in its fight for our divine provenance.
That is just what
we were thinking.
Come here, come here.
I know you want to
play the war game,
but I'm not going anywhere
with these psychopaths.
If you don't like 'em,
once we get to the front,
you can just kill them
and join the revolutionaries.
No, Logan. Enough is
enough. I'm not doing this.
You actually let loose for once,
you shoot an unarmed man,
and now you feel bad because
you can't call yourself the hero.
Don't you get it yet?
There is no such thing
as heroes or villains.
It's just a giant circle jerk.
I think that philosophy says way more
about you than it does about the world.
And you, you see
the world so clearly?
You probably think you're on this trip
because you're some kind of contender,
some threat to me?
I picked you precisely because
you will never be a threat to anyone.
My sister probably picked
you for the same reason.
I earned my place.
Nobody handed it to me.
Right. A lifetime of working
hard, following the rules,
and you finally reach the
pinnacle of your career trajectory...
Executive Vice President.
Upper middle management.
Do you remember the day that you finally
got those three fancy little letters?
EVP.
You walked into my office in
that cheap black suit of yours,
and you shook my hand and
you thanked me for the opportunity.
That was the best
day of your life.
Right, buddy.
That's what I thought.
What does it mean?
The maze.
You must follow the maze.
What's wrong with me?
Perhaps, you are unraveling.
Right here.
Easy pumping
that nitro into him.
Fill the empties with
tequila and seal them up.
Your work for the revolution
is not quite done yet, my friend.
Careful.
Slim always had a bad temper.
William, we have to go now.
Lazo's been conning
us the whole time.
He was never going to give the nitro
to the Confederados. We have to run!
Of course we do.
That's how this
place works, right?
They create an urgency
and a sense of danger,
so they can strip us down to
something raw, animalistic, primal.
It's a sick game, and I
don't want to be a part of it.
This isn't a game.
They'll kill us.
But together, I know
we can find a way out.
How can you be sure?
There's a voice inside me,
telling me what I have to do.
And it's telling me I need you.
Shit.
They have Logan.
Help me.
No.
No more pretending.
I thought you had no
appetite for war, boy.
This is a declaration of war.
El Lazo set us up.
We can find him for you.
You can find him for
us by joining him in hell.
Dolores, run!
Dolores?
How did you do that?
You said people come here to
change the story of their lives.
I imagined a story where I
didn't have to be the damsel.
Now that train is our only chance
of making it out of here alive.
Motherfuckers.
You pull that trigger, we'll
all go up in a ball of hellfire.
So, why don't you
loosen your grip a mite?
It's okay.
I don't trust him.
Which is the first step
to truly knowing me.
Give me your gun, El Lazo.
Now that we're all friends,
you can call me Lawrence.
Now, why don't we settle
in. It's a long ride to the front.
You want a sip of this swill?
Don't worry, it ain't nitro.
I'm coming.
The girls are a little worn
out, but I can rouse one.
You boys want some company?
No. Just whiskey.
Lawrence's donation
must be running low.
But we're short on time.
You need to buck up, Teddy.
I told you, no company.
Thought I might join you, anyway,
as I never like to drink alone.
Well, isn't this a rare honor?
Teddy, you know who this is?
Can't say that I do.
Everything good that has
ever happened in your life,
and everything rotten, this
is the man you have to thank.
How am I doing, Robert?
Any closer to finding
what I'm looking for?
And what is that, exactly?
We're looking for a
man named Wyatt.
Killed a rancher back in
Sweetwater, took his daughter.
That last part
doesn't sound familiar.
Figured your stories could
use a little embellishment.
You know, I always felt this
place was missing a real villain,
hence my humble contribution.
I admit, I lack the imagination to
even conceive of someone like you.
The urgency, however,
doesn't quite fit the character.
It betrays a certain anxiety.
Now, Wyatt, on the other
hand, that's something new.
Is he just another stooge for the
tourists to mount on their wall at home,
or have you finally
made a worthy adversary?
Someone to stop me from
finding the center of the maze.
And what is it you're
hoping to find there?
You know why you exist, Teddy?
The world out there,
the one you'll never see,
is one of plenty.
A fat, soft teat people
cling to their entire life.
Every need taken care of,
except one.
Purpose.
Meaning.
So, they come here.
They can be a little
scared, a little thrilled,
enjoy some sweetly
affirmative bullshit,
and then they take a fucking
picture and they go back home.
But I think there's
a deeper meaning
hiding under all that.
Something that the person
who created it wanted to express.
Something true.
Well, if you're looking
for the moral of the story,
you could quite simply ask.
I'd need a shovel.
The man I'd be asking
died 35 years ago.
Almost took this place with him.
Almost, but not
quite. Thanks to me.
Well, maybe he left
something behind.
I wonder what I would
find if I opened you up.
Even at death's door,
you're still a loyal pet.
Is that why you
came here, Robert?
To try to talk me out of it?
On the contrary.
Far be it from me to get in the
way of a voyage of self-discovery.
Mr. Flood.
We must look back and
smile at perils past, mustn't we?
We should get back on
the road. Time's a-wasting.
Hello, Felix.
It's time you and I had a chat.
English -SDH