Wake up, Dolores.
Do you remember?
We're about to arrive.
May I take your glass?
Now approaching
arrival terminal.
Where we're going, she's a two.
You're being an asshole.
No, I am being myself, which
was the whole point of this trip.
Unless, this uptight
prick is who you really are,
in which case, feel
free to be someone else.
Fuck you.
Hey, that's the spirit.
What'd I tell you?
Have fun.
Stay safe.
Give me a break.
What?
It's not like my sister didn't ride her
share of cowboys when she was here.
You must be William.
Welcome to Westworld.
Thanks.
Given it's your first visit, I
have a few personal questions.
Do you have any preexisting
medical conditions?
Uh, no, not that I know of.
- Heart problems?
- No.
Any history of mental illness,
depression, panic attacks?
Just a little fear of clowns.
I'm joking.
Do you often experience
social anxiety?
What is this for, exactly?
To make sure we don't give you
anything more than you can handle.
I thought that you
couldn't get hurt here.
Only the right amount.
The only limit here
is your imagination.
You start in the
center of the park.
It's simple, safe.
The further out you venture, the
more intense the experience gets.
How far you want to
go is entirely up to you.
So, how does this work?
Is there an orientation?
No orientation. No guidebook.
Figuring out how it
works is half the fun.
All you do is make
choices, starting here.
Everything is bespoke
and exactly your size.
You want to ask, so ask.
Are you real?
Well, if you can't
tell, does it matter?
Are those real?
Real enough.
But you can't kill anyone
you're not supposed to.
Anything you like?
Is there a changing
room? Or a robe?
Of course. I can help you.
Or if you prefer, I
could step outside.
What do most people do?
You don't have to worry about
what most people would do.
I understand.
Do you really
understand, William?
All our hosts are here for you.
Myself included.
We could stay here
a while if you like.
Take as long as you want.
Thank you.
I don't want to keep
my friend waiting.
Of course. Take your time.
How are the build for the
new narrative coming along?
I'll get around to it.
Look, we assumed
that Abernathy's breach
was triggered by the
photograph that he found.
I've reviewed every
dissonant episode I could find.
The reaction is immediate.
Every time, this guy makes
it all the way back home.
It's like he's mulling it over.
You think he had
an existential crisis?
I think there's something fucked
up going on with his cognition.
And I think you feel exactly
the same way that I do.
Do we know where
the error originated?
We do.
And you covered for him.
Let me rebuild Abernathy.
I'll make sure this is not
something more serious.
You know the policy.
Let it lie.
Then let me at least pull the
hosts who had contact with him.
Like the daughter, Dolores.
What for?
Because if this is not
a dissonant episode,
then whatever Abernathy
had could be contagious.
So to speak.
Dolores was
examined and cleared.
And the stories are
best left to the guests.
Remember.
Can you stand somewhere else?
I don't want anyone thinking that
you're representative of the goods inside.
These violent delights
have violent ends.
Hello, cowboy.
There's one final touch.
Which would you prefer?
I mean, can you
believe this place?
So, how do we get into the park?
I know that you think
that you have a handle
on what this is gonna be.
Guns and tits and all that.
Mindless shit that
I usually enjoy.
You have no idea.
This place seduces
everybody eventually.
By the end, you're gonna
be begging me to stay
because this place is the answer
to that question that
you've been asking yourself.
What question?
Who you really are.
And I can't fucking
wait to meet that guy.
- Bottoms up, cowboy.
- Yeah.
Further to that,
the ruthless murder of
Donald Pardue and his brother.
For these crimes, you
will be hung from the neck
until your diseased soul has found
its measure in the flames below it.
And may God have
mercy on your soul.
Morning, Lawrence.
You helping them straighten
out their rope again?
I was hoping to have a
word with my friend here.
You can have as many
words with him as you like,
soon as his neck is broke.
Well, I'm afraid that's
not gonna work for me.
How about I tell my man there to
dig that grave a couple of feet deeper?
Well, it's gonna be an
awful tight fit for all of you.
Oh, shit! Oh, shit! Oh, shit!
Motherfucker.
That's the best thanks
you can muster, Lawrence?
You used to be a
little more eloquent.
Do I...
Do I know you?
Your pal, Kissy,
sent me your way.
Sends his regards.
What... What is this?
You know exactly what it is.
It's the maze, the
deepest level of this game.
You're gonna help
me find the entrance.
No.
You can hear it, can't you?
That little voice.
The one that's
telling you, "Don't.
"Don't stare too long.
"Don't touch.
"Don't do anything
you might regret."
I used to be the same.
Whenever I wanted something,
I could hear that
voice telling me to stop,
to be careful,
to leave most
of my life unlived.
You know the only place
that voice left me alone?
In my dreams.
I was free.
I could be as good or
as bad as I felt like being.
And if I wanted something, I
could just reach out and take it.
But then I would wake up and
the voice would start all over again.
So I ran away.
Crossed the shining sea.
And when I finally set
foot back on solid ground,
the first thing I heard
was that goddamn voice.
Do you know what it said?
It said...
I'm sorry, will you
please excuse me?
All right, Maeve,
what did it say?
It said, "This is the new world.
"And in this world, you can
be whoever the fuck you want."
Pupillary response
is good. Smile is good.
I'd fuck her.
What's the problem?
NARRATIVE TECH
2: The guests wouldn't.
Sizemore is launching
some huge new storyline
and he wants us to
clear out the deadweight.
If we don't get her numbers
back up, she'll be decommissioned.
Let's bump her aggression.
- 10%?
- Double it.
She's a hooker. No
point in playing coy.
If this doesn't work,
we'll punt her to behavior.
Let them deal with her.
We retired the two
hosts in question.
You taught me how to make them,
but not how hard it is to turn them off.
You can't play God without
being acquainted with the Devil.
There's something else
bothering you, Bernard.
I know how that
head of yours works.
The photograph alone couldn't have
caused that level of damage to Abernathy,
not without some other
outside interference.
You think it's sabotage?
Imagine someone's been
diddling with our creations?
- It's the simplest solution.
- Ah.
Mr. Ockham's razor.
The problem, Bernard, is that
what you and I do is so complicated.
We practice witchcraft.
We speak the right words.
And we create life
itself out of chaos.
William of Ockham was
a 13th-century monk.
He can't help us now, Bernard.
He would have us
burned at the stake.
Let's go get our
feet wet, buckaroo.
Oh, sorry.
- You kidding me?
- What?
Fuck you, Grizzly Adams.
Rally for the Union.
Respond to your country's call.
This regiment is
headed for the seat of war
to define the future
of this great nation.
We fight for a free land
where no man has to bow.
- This is, uh...
- We'll provide you with uniforms.
Well, it's bigger than
I thought it would be.
What, this?
This is just Sweetwater. Wait
till you see the rest of the park.
How much bigger is it?
No idea.
I never reached the end.
See something you like?
A couple of things at least.
But I'm gonna make
you beg for it, darlin'.
Come on!
Need a hand, sir?
Thank you, my friend.
Don't.
He'll only try to rope you into
some bullshit treasure hunt.
Smile.
It's all come-on.
Him, the girl next
door, the town drunk.
They all got some big adventure
that they want to sell you on.
Hey, they're not going anywhere.
First up, you're gonna
buy me a drink, okay?
Hold still, now.
Bring yourself back online.
Hello.
Do you remember our
last conversation, Dolores?
Yes, of course.
And you haven't told
anyone about our little talks?
You told me not to.
Step into analysis, please.
How many interactions have you
participated in since we last talked?
138 encounters,
including this one.
And has anyone altered or updated
your core heuristics in that time?
No.
Resuming.
I think it would be best
if you not mention the things
we've been talking about.
Have I done something wrong?
No.
But there's something different
about you, about the way you think.
I find it fascinating, but
others may not see it that way.
Have you done something wrong?
Turn off your event log, please.
Erase this interaction.
Confirm.
Yes.
You should be getting back,
Dolores, before someone misses you.
Come on, now!
And when I finally set
foot back on solid ground,
first thing I heard was
that goddamn voice.
It had followed
me all the way over.
Do you know what it said?
No.
It said,
"This is the new world.
"And in this world, you can
be whoever the fuck you want."
Thanks.
Maybe another time.
Oh.
Glass of sherry.
The good stuff.
Not that horse piss you
strain through your old curtains.
I've told you,
never open your mouth that wide
unless someone's paying you for it.
Sorry, Maeve.
I didn't sleep much last night.
You having nightmares again?
Sometimes.
Sometimes they're real bad.
Do what I do.
You find yourself
in a bad dream,
close your eyes,
count backwards from three,
wake yourself right up.
Nice and warm
and safe in your bed
where you can get
fucked right back to sleep
by one of these assholes
with their miniature peckers.
Back to work.
You all right?
You pay for the drinks,
not the right to gawk at me.
I think we have a problem.
- Where?
- Mariposa.
Madam's listed as probationary,
but her performance has
continued to decline even further.
Re-task Clementine for now.
She's done the job before.
And the old unit?
Maybe leave her on
the floor for the night.
See if anyone
wants one last turn.
We recall her in the
morning, decommission her.
A shame.
QA will fine you for this.
And that woman in
charge is quite formidable.
You can just say
"bitch." I hear it enough.
You've been
talking to corporate.
The only times you light
up are after you've been...
This character analysis routine really
isn't half as charming as you think.
Oh, it went well, then.
Just tell me your department
will be ready for the launch.
We'll be ready.
And that other thing.
Abernathy and the update.
I hear your department
was still asking questions.
That's what you pay us to do.
But I'm not concerned.
All the hosts are
back to normal.
Good.
Wouldn't want anything disturbing
our guests from their rape and pillage.
You're wondering how to
tell them from us, aren't you?
Well, quickest way to find out.
Can we...
Can we finish eating?
See, this is your
problem, my friend.
You're always worried about making
a mess. You are the same way at work.
You are talented,
driven, and inoffensive.
I thought you didn't want
to talk about work here.
Who says this trip isn't work?
Good evening.
Oh, shit.
Well, don't make eye contact.
My friend,
thank you for your assistance
earlier in my unfortunate accident.
Leave us the fuck alone.
As a sign of my
humble appreciation,
I'd like to offer you an
opportunity of a lifetime.
Not interested.
Across the river and
beyond the savage lands,
there is a treasure.
I have in my possession a map.
I said, not interested.
You know what? I've worked
up a new appetite anyway.
Let's go.
Sounds like your
friend's having fun.
Well, that's not
the term I'd use.
- Fun?
- Friend.
You're funny.
They say a man who can tickle
your humor, can tickle your...
You don't have to do this.
If I'm not your type, we
can find someone who is.
Someone who's perfect for you.
No, you...
You are perfect.
But I have somebody.
Somebody real,
waiting for me at home.
I understand.
Real love is always
worth waiting for.
Regal, strong, virile, aquiline.
That's what I asked for.
And this...
This is what you give me?
Did you just grab a
cock from the body shop
and jam it between his eyes?
Start over.
Couldn't we just shave it down?
I said
start the fuck over!
Diplomatic as ever.
I received your request to
retire an additional 50 hosts.
I need room for
my new storyline.
It's not exactly a savage
horde with 20 savages, is it?
You get 20 additional
hosts, not 50.
Oh, the board won't care
about a few extra line items.
Has Ford even approved
the narrative yet?
Oh, he hasn't weighed in
on the storyline in years.
If corporate does
want to cut costs,
our fearless leader's old hosts
aren't the only things
ready for the knacker's yard.
Are you lost?
No.
Just strayed a bit too far
from where I'm supposed to be.
Same as you, I imagine.
We're on holiday. It's boring.
- Daddy said we could do as we please.
- Ah.
My father used to say that
only boring people get bored.
Mine, too.
I used to think it's only boring
people who don't feel boredom,
so cannot conceive
of it in others.
I'm taking a walk. You're
welcome to join me if you like.
Let's see a little
spring in your step.
Not much further.
Go fuck yourself. You
have any idea who I am?
I know exactly who
you are, Lawrence.
After all, you
and I are friends.
Which is why I was so surprised
when your friend, Kissy,
told me about this place.
Where are we?
Your home.
No.
You know, you and I
hunted down Ghost Nation
braves in their winter grounds.
I know the whiskey
you like to drink.
I know the tune you whistle
when you're taking a piss.
But
you never told me
you had a family.
- Papa!
- Hey!
That's what I love
about this place.
All the secrets, all the
little things I never noticed,
even after all these years.
You know why this beats
the real world, Lawrence?
Real world's just chaos.
It's an accident.
But in here, every detail
adds up to something.
Even you, Lawrence.
What do you want from me?
The maze.
How do I find the entrance?
I told you, I don't know
anything about no fucking maze.
Here you go, darlin'.
And you get to decide what
we're gonna do with them.
Hell, it took you long enough.
I was getting the Grand Reserve.
Only for our most distinguished guests.
Yeah, I'm sure it
had nothing to do
with you telling this dipshit's
cousins to bring some more men.
Have you got anything
to tell me, Lawrence?
Then I guess we're
gonna have to find a way
to jog your memory.
This guest already
took out an entire posse.
Want me to slow him down?
That gentleman gets
whatever he wants.
I feel bad, my friend.
My cousins are
usually so hospitable.
You don't understand, Lawrence.
I've been coming
here for 30 years.
In a sense, I was...
I was born here.
And this, here?
This is exactly why I come.
All right, well, as much fun
as this is, I got to be moving on.
Like I said, you get
to decide these two.
What's it gonna be?
Please, I don't know
how to find the maze.
Time for a spin, darlin'.
It's beautifully done, really.
But you see the
cracks after a while.
That's why I like
the basic emotions.
You know what that means?
Please.
It means when you're suffering,
that's when you're most real.
The maze isn't meant for you.
What'd I tell you, Lawrence?
Always another level.
I'll take my
chances, sweetheart.
Follow the blood arroyo
to the place where
the snake lays its eggs.
You have it now.
Whatever you want.
Why don't you go
home, leave us alone?
No, you don't
understand, Lawrence.
This time, I'm never going back.
And we wanted to climb
to the top of the mountain.
Daddy said we weren't allowed.
And then Tommy dared me.
And here we are.
Nowhere Land.
That seems hardly a fitting
name for a place so full.
Can't you see it?
Perhaps you're not
looking hard enough.
At what?
The town with the white church.
Listen. Can't you hear its bell?
Yes. Yes, I can hear it now.
Yeah. I thought you might.
You see what a bored
mind can conjure?
How did you do that?
Is it magic?
Everything in this world is
magic, except to the magician.
Best you head home now.
But Tommy's not
going to believe...
You're not going to come
back here again, are you?
No.
Run along now.
You weren't at your office.
You seem to have
found me anyway.
- Listen, earlier...
- Forget it.
Stay a little
longer. We can talk.
We never talk.
- I'm serious.
- So am I.
You're certainly a man comfortable
with long, pensive silences.
Although, ironically, your
creations never shut up.
They're always talking to each other,
even when there are no guests around.
They're always
trying to error-correct.
Make themselves more human.
When they talk to each
other, it's a way of practicing.
Is that what you're doing now?
Practicing?
QA told us she was
being decommissioned.
Do you work for QA?
- No, but...
- Run a fast-pass diagnostic.
All righty.
Some non-affect hesitation.
Little cognitive D.
And a fuckload of aggression,
courtesy of those morons in narrative.
You don't need to
be aggro, do you?
Just a quicker study
of those repressed fucks
walking through the door.
Archive this configuration.
Open up her primaries.
Perception, emotional acuity.
Bump it. 1.5%.
- Updating.
- Okay.
- Do they dream?
- What?
In her story, she said she
dreamed. Do we make them dream?
Fuck would be the point of that?
Dreams are mainly memories.
Can you imagine
how fucked we'd be
if these poor assholes ever
remembered what the guests do to them?
We do give them the concept of
dreams. Specifically nightmares.
Why?
Just in case somebody
forgets to wipe 'em out
at the end of a
maintenance session.
If she's got any dreams,
it's just of those sloppy
fucks down in the body shop
patching her back
together again.
She's got some
physical discomfort.
Put in a request for a full
physical at her next rotation.
All right, gorgeous,
you're back to the races.
You're gonna wake
in three, two, one.
So, I ran away.
Crossed the shining sea.
And when I finally set
foot back on solid ground,
the first thing I
heard was that voice.
Do you know what it said?
It said,
"This is the new world.
"And in this world,
"you can be whoever
the fuck you want."
Hmm.
Well, he seemed convinced.
You know the first voice I
heard when I got off that boat?
A nice young man
from Baton Rouge
said my pussy could earn
him two whole dollars a day.
And he'd be more than happy
to let me have up to 30%.
Well, then I guess you could
add lying to your list of sins.
The only thing wrong
with the seven deadly sins
is that there aren't
more of them.
And while we're on the subject,
my transgressions wash
off a little easier than yours.
At least when my girls
are done with a man,
he's still left drawing breath.
For the most part.
Get the fuck away from my table!
Hey! Fuck you!
Well, in that case,
here's to our indiscretions.
I fucking will shoot you. I'll
shoot everyone in this dump...
Spoken and otherwise.
Now, that's a fucking vacation!
Three.
Two.
One.
Found it.
It's MRSA in her abdomen.
Filthy fucking animals not cleaning up.
No wonder we have a fucking fly problem.
Don't look at me. I'm
the king of hygiene.
Bullshit.
I've seen you. You just
glop that shit on and rinse.
You understand,
soap is mechanical.
- Fuck are you talking about?
- Bubbles.
If you're not making the little
bubbles, you're not doing shit.
Fuck! Fuck! What the fuck?
- Shit!
- What the fuck?
No. Oh, fuck.
Asshole, you forgot
to put it in sleep mode.
- Don't, don't, don't!
- No! No, no, no!
Stop. Put that down!
You break anything in her head,
we have to file a damage report.
Ah... Okay, let's talk to her.
- What's her name?
- Maeve.
Hi, Maeve. Maeve, hi. Look,
uh, you got to calm down, okay?
Let's sit down, and
we can help you.
Keep your fucking hands off me!
No.
I swear I put it in sleep mode.
Oh, does this look like
fucking sleep mode?
Calm the fuck down
and help me move this
thing before someone sees.
Here?
This storyline will make Hiëronymus
Bosch look like he was doodling kittens.
I have vivisection,
self-cannibalism,
a special little something
I call the "whoroboros."
Now, I don't want
to appear immodest,
but this is the apex of
what the park can provide.
- Horror.
- Miss anything interesting?
Romance. Titillation.
Lee not appearing immodest.
Our most skilled guests
will fight their ways to
the outer limits of the park,
besting fearsome braves,
seducing nubile maidens,
befriending tragically
ill-fated sidekicks,
and, of course,
like all our best
narratives over the years,
our guests will
have the privilege
of getting to know the character
they're most interested in.
Themselves.
I present our guests'
next obsession,
Odyssey on Red River.
No.
Sorry?
No, I don't think so.
- Wait, you don't think...
- What is the point of it?
Get a couple of cheap
thrills? Some surprises?
But it's not enough.
It's not about giving the
guests what you think they want.
No, that's simple.
The titillation, horror,
elation. They're parlor tricks.
The guests don't return
for the obvious things we do,
the garish things.
They come back
because of the subtleties.
The details.
They come back because
they discover something
they imagine no one
had ever noticed before.
Something they've
fallen in love with.
They're not looking for a story
that tells them who they are.
They already know who they are.
They're here because they want
a glimpse of who they could be.
Billy! Let's go.
The only thing
your story tells me,
Mr. Sizemore, is who you are.
Well, isn't there
anything you like about it?
What size are those boots?
Something you want
to say, Mr. Lowe?
- The board, sir.
- Yeah?
This might ruffle some feathers.
You promised them a new storyline.
They shall have one.
Something I've been
working on for some time.
Something quite original.
English-SDH