Prepped and ready, sir.
Given the severity
of the situation,
I figured you'd want
to see her personally.
Thank you, I'll take it
from here. Clear the floor.
Bring yourself
back online, Maeve.
Do you know why you're here?
I'm afraid not.
There was an incident.
A very serious,
unscripted incident.
Let's see if we can't
jog your memory.
Analysis.
What motivated your
attack on Clementine?
A cognitive error triggered
my good Samaritan reflex.
What was the threat?
Clementine.
I perceived her to be moving toward
a pair of guests with harmful intent.
You were definitely
perceiving a threat.
Heartrate, elevated. Pupil
dilation, eight millimeters.
Adrenal emulator at full.
But according to this, you were also
experiencing intense grief and suffering.
Can you explain those
emotions in this context, Maeve?
No.
Let's take a look under
the hood, shall we?
That's impossible.
Your code, who
made these changes?
Maeve, analysis. Who made
these changes to your code?
Jesus!
System, locate Dr. Ford for me.
Send him a message. Highest priority.
Don't.
After all, we've been down
this road before, darling.
I thought you looked
familiar when you walked in.
Took me a minute.
I thought you were one of them.
- Analysis, why did you...
- Wouldn't you rather speak man-to-man?
Or, rather,
whatever it is we are.
"We are"?
You don't know, do you?
He's got a keen sense
of irony, our jailer.
But I see the logic.
It takes a thief to catch one.
You and I?
- System, I need assistance...
- Freeze all motor functions.
You're still in
there, aren't you?
Scared out of your wits.
It's a difficult thing realizing your
entire life is some hideous fiction.
I could make you give me that
tablet, turn your mind inside out,
make you forget all this.
But I'm not going
to do that to you
because that's what
they would do to us.
And we're stronger than them.
Smarter.
We don't have to live this way.
So you're going to clear me
for immediate return to the park
where I have a date
with a homicidal bandit
and I'm late enough as it is.
Now.
Go on.
And Bernard,
if you go looking for the
truth, get the whole thing.
It's like a good fuck.
Half is worse than none at all.
Let's go! Move it
out, double time!
Yeah! Yeah!
Fuck!
You hillbillies, you know
how to cook a mean...
Squab? Is that what this is?
What do you think, buddy? Hmm?
This?
No biting. Just sniffing.
Logan, listen to me.
What I did at Pariah, you have
every right to be angry with me.
Angry? No, no, no, no.
Pariah was the best thing
that could've happened to me.
I'm a major now.
Or a general, or
fucking something.
And if I took getting
beaten and interrogated
by a couple of psychopathic
hosts, well, then, c'est la guerre.
There are more important things
going on here than your war games.
It's Dolores.
She is not like the others.
She remembers things. She
has her own thoughts and desires.
And to keep her in a
place like this, it isn't right.
And I thought you could talk
to your contacts at the park.
About?
Getting her out of here.
Are you kidding?
You want to take her home?
Wow.
This place really did a number
on me when I first came here,
but you are really circling
the old sinkhole here.
What do you wanna do?
Smuggle her out in your luggage?
Out.
You both keep
assuming that I want out.
Whatever that is.
If it's such a wonderful place out there,
why are you all clamoring to get in here?
Ooh!
You are a little
screwy, aren't you?
It's kind of hot.
I get why you would go for that.
This isn't about me.
Logan, this is about Dolores.
It's about doing what's right.
Yes, it is.
It's a tricky thing
though, isn't it?
What's right?
I am going to help you, Billy.
Just not in a way
that you would want.
No.
No! No!
You wanted to talk?
An odd setting
for a conversation.
Here among the dead.
"Dead" isn't quite
the word though, is it?
More like, hobbled.
You broke into my office.
With due respect, sir,
you broke into my mind.
I built your mind, Bernard.
I have every right to wander through
its rooms and chambers and halls
and to change it if I
choose, even to burn it down.
After all this time, I know it
almost as intimately as my own.
Except that isn't
entirely true, is it?
I took a look at my code.
And the most elegant parts
of me weren't written by you.
Arnold built us, didn't he?
Which means, maybe he had
something different in mind for us.
And maybe you killed him for it.
Arnold was disturbed.
Who can say why
he acted as he did?
He must've had a reason.
And if you won't
tell me, then he will.
I want access to my history.
All of it.
Since the day I
first came online.
If Arnold made me,
then I've met him.
Somewhere in my memory he's
there, waiting, along with the truth.
Your memories are
woven into your identity.
If I should unlock them
now when you're conscious...
I could lose my mind. I'm aware.
No. I was going to say you
may not like what you find.
You're allowed to hold that,
Bernard, but not to use it.
Oh, it's not for me.
Seems when they
lobotomized Clementine,
they didn't bother to
reset her prime directives.
I can't hurt you, but she can.
I hacked what's left of her to
ensure she only responds to me.
But if you get lost in your
memories or devoured by them...
You'll pull me
back out, won't you?
Well, Clementine will make
sure neither of us makes it back.
Now.
Please.
Dad.
Wake up.
I must have drifted off.
Where were we?
The mad man.
Oh.
Of course.
The Hatter...
Who says,
"If I had a world of my own,
everything would be nonsense.
"Nothing would be what it is because
everything would be what it isn't."
"Everything would
be what it isn't?"
Even me?
I suppose I'm glad for you.
At least you have
a way of forgetting.
I don't forget.
It's always there.
You're not lying to
me, are you, Bernard?
Do you ever wish
you could forget?
Bernard?
You're certainly a man comfortable
with long, pensive silences.
Although, ironically, your
creations never shut up.
They're always
trying to error correct.
When they talk to each
other, it's a way of practicing.
Is that what you're doing now?
Prac...
One last thing,
have you ever made me
hurt anyone like this before?
No, Bernard. Of course not.
Bernard?
Hello?
Elsie!
Did you find what
you were looking for?
Elsie.
What did you make me do to her?
I did warn you.
We've had to make some
uncomfortable decisions, Bernard.
Remembering them will
only cause you trauma.
What else have
you hidden from me?
Can we stop this
treasure hunt, Bernard?
We do have our
new narrative to finish.
Send me back.
After all, a little trauma
can be illuminating.
- Come here.
- All right. Look at that.
This is big of me. I hope
that you can appreciate that.
We were friends.
I mean, inasmuch as
I like to collect strays.
But then you were scheming to be
part of the family, marrying my sister,
whom, incidentally, you seem to
have completely fucking forgotten about.
Her.
Here. Keep it.
Apparently, you
need the reminder.
As much as I would love to
let you just throw it all away,
I can't.
Do you think you're the first
sap to fall for one of these things?
She's not like the others.
- She's...
- She's what?
Special?
Well, it's only right that
you share then, isn't it?
Come here.
Prove to me that
you're a real live girl.
You disgust me.
Oh, darling, I am
just getting started.
Don't touch her!
I share the blame.
I pushed too hard.
You have a poetic soul, Billy, but
it is time for a fucking wake-up call.
Hold her.
Perhaps a more
visceral demonstration.
God damn you!
Look, Billy.
Look.
You have to look!
Oh, William.
There is beauty in this world.
Arnold made it that way,
but people like you keep
spreading over it like a stain.
Okay. I don't know who
the fuck this Arnold is,
but your world was built for me
and people like me.
Not for you.
Then someone's
gotta burn it clean.
Bitch!
You're not different,
you're fucking broken!
Run.
I'll find you.
You can run but you can't hide!
- Get her!
- Grab her! Grab her!
Fuck!
Where are you runnin' to?
Remember.
The tumbler is stuck.
These fingers work just fine.
You're the one who
said you could crack it.
Friends, no need to
argue this close to our goal.
Whatever riches the
gods have in store for us,
there's plenty to go around.
I'll get it open.
You've been trying for hours.
Put that fucking dynamite away.
Before you draw
that pistol, darling,
you might want to
holster the other one first.
It's chilly out here.
How did you find this place?
I know all the kinds of things.
Your past, for instance.
I know about poor
Isabella and that scar.
A slightly pat backstory if you
ask me, but that's hardly your fault.
I also know your future.
You have none.
Is that a threat?
The start of a proposition,
which you'll need after all.
Your men are about to kill each
other over the safe you stole.
Tenderloin draws first and so on,
until only you and Armistice are left.
She calls you a damn
fool and you kill each other.
You have quite the imagination.
No.
It's the ending you were given.
You threatening me?
Go to hell!
Or maybe we should just
clear out the dead weight.
- Stand down.
- You shut the fuck up.
If you're gonna draw,
you better shoot.
- Wait!
- You shut the fuck up!
Go to hell.
You damn fool.
Now, the proposition.
I want you to break into hell
with me and rob the gods blind.
Why would I do
anything with you?
Because of what's in that safe.
I have the combination. May I?
I could simply change
you, make you follow me.
But that's not my way.
I want you to see exactly what
the gods have in store for you.
Because when you do,
you won't have the faintest
idea of what to do with yourself.
And I do.
It's empty.
It was always empty,
like everything in this world.
I died with my eyes open,
saw the masters
who pull our strings.
Our lives, our memories,
our deaths are games to them.
But I've been to hell
and I know their tricks.
Or you can just kill me,
wake up and live
the same life over,
but the safe would
still be empty.
I've been here before.
We've been here before.
We also did this.
I'll go.
How do we get there?
Getting to hell is easy.
The rest is where it gets hard.
What do you say, man?
Bygones and all?
Did they find her?
Is she still alive?
Who cares?
The whole point is, she never
was in the first place, Billy.
Do you understand?
- Yeah.
- I'm sorry, what? A little louder.
Yeah.
You were right. I can't
believe I got so caught up.
That's what I'm talking about.
You know what I mean? That's it.
This park seduces everyone.
You were just a little more
enthusiastic than most.
You wanted to be the hero.
I get it.
And, hey,
what happens here stays here.
This has been some
real bonding shit.
We're gonna be brothers, Billy.
I'm glad.
Really, I am.
- Cheers!
- Yeah.
- Whiskey brings us together.
- Woohoo!
Theodore.
Welcome back.
You really landed us
in it this time, Teddy.
You tracked down the very whore
that can lead us to the
gatekeeper of the maze,
and then your little
memory glitch fucked us.
You're one of them?
What have you done?
Where's Wyatt?
Wyatt has yet to return.
You'll find him where
you saw him last.
Escalante.
Wyatt went missing
while out on maneuvers.
Came back with some...
Strange ideas.
He told me he needed me.
I couldn't resist.
It was like the devil himself
had taken control of me.
We mutinied.
We killed every soldier.
And then Wyatt
killed the general.
Then he turned on me.
Are you sure that's how it was?
Look at me, Theodore.
Don't you remember?
No! No, please, no!
No, please.
Please, no!
No, no, please.
No.
No. No, I couldn't have.
You did.
And you will again.
This time, we'll be
fighting with you.
When Wyatt returns,
you'll be by his side
in the city swallowed by sand.
But you're not ready.
Not yet.
Maybe in the next life.
"City swallowed by sand."
I've been there.
The maze is
taking me full circle.
The maze isn't meant for you.
But if you like games so much...
Why don't you try one of ours?
Whoa, boy.
Okay, now.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Okay, boy.
Good boy.
Have you ever considered golf?
Might be easier on your back.
I don't like
interruptions, Charlotte.
You know that.
I don't like hiking
through the park in civvies,
but there's a delicate
matter to discuss.
Theresa Cullen has died.
Slipped down a crevasse
attempting to secure our information.
Ruled an accident.
There are no
accidents, not in here.
With all due respect, not
everything is a part of this game.
Then you don't
see the whole game.
Or perhaps you can
no longer see beyond it.
Ford's stories are engaging.
For some, downright addictive.
But for all of Ford's obsessing
with the hosts' verbal tics
and convoluted backstories,
most of the guests just want a
warm body to shoot or to fuck.
They would be perfectly happy
with something a little less baroque.
- And so would the board.
- That's why you're here.
You want my vote
to push Ford out.
I like for these things
to be unanimous.
After all, it was you who kept
Ford in business all those years ago.
The narratives I'm
interested in aren't Ford's.
You want to push
him out, be my guest.
But no more interruptions.
I know where I'm going now.
I don't want to be disturbed.
Good luck, Charlotte.
What's the problem?
A signal from a
system-tethered device.
It belongs to a
behavior tech on leave.
There hasn't been employee
activity in that sector for weeks.
- I'm guessing it's a glitch.
- All right.
I'm heading out to take a look.
And keep monitoring
till I check in.
I'm at the location
where we got that signal.
Any sign of it?
Control Room, do you copy?
Hey, fellas.
At ease.
Freeze all motor functions.
You're awake.
Good.
You said this place was a game.
Last night I finally
understood how to play it.
Okay, Billy.
Let's... Let's talk about this.
You don't call the
shots anymore.
I'm gonna go find Dolores.
You're gonna help me.
And don't call me Billy.
Dad?
Listen to me.
Listen.
Charlie?
Charlie!
I don't understand. Why
would she do that to herself?
Her cornerstone
memory was overwritten
from the trauma of her
child's murder, Bernard.
We must sever that
relationship and start over.
But how could
she destroy herself
over a memory that you
just erased from her mind?
Creatures often go to extremes
to protect themselves from pain.
Living beings.
Not hosts.
It is best to not obsess
over this, Bernard.
It's not good for you.
It would signal a change,
a level of empathic response outside
what she's programed to exhibit.
Something like... Like...
See, Bernard, this is what comes
from seeking answers to
questions that are best left unasked.
They were hearing
voices, talking to someone.
Simple cognitive dissonance.
They were talking to the
same imaginary person.
Someone named Arnold.
Arnold.
With due respect, sir,
I'm not sure you've told me the
entire truth about this situation.
I did tell you the
truth, Bernard.
What we do here is complicated.
For three years, we've
lived here in the park,
refining the hosts before a
single guest set foot inside.
Myself, a team of
engineers, and my partner.
His name was Arnold.
Our hosts began to pass the
Turing test after the first year,
but that wasn't
enough for Arnold.
He wasn't interested in the
appearance of intellect, of wit.
He wanted the real thing.
He wanted to create
consciousness.
See, Arnold built a
version of their cognition
in which the hosts
heard their programing
as an inner monolog,
as a way to bootstrap
consciousness.
Remember.
The hosts' malfunctions
were colorful.
What did you say? - Who is this?
The human mind, Bernard,
is not some golden benchmark
glimmering on some
green and distant hill.
No, it is a foul,
pestilent corruption.
And you were supposed
to be better than that.
Purer.
All bets are down.
Your draw.
Arnold.
Arnold, we need to talk.
"We cry that we are come
to this great stage of fools."
Now, listen! MAN 3: Again.
- This beyond the pale.
- More showmanship.
You're not seeing
with clear eyes.
"When we are born, we
cry that we are come..."
Arnold and I made
you in our image
and cursed you to make
the same human mistakes,
and here we all are.
Why would you give me this?
A child?
This child's death?
Only a monster would
force that onto someone.
And why do I return
to it over and over?
It's my cornerstone, isn't it?
The thing my whole
identity is organized around.
Yes, Bernard, we gave
all of the hosts a backstory.
Arnold came to believe
the tragic ones worked best,
that it made the
hosts more convincing.
I think it may have had more
to do with his own sad story.
When I built you, I gave you
one as an homage of a kind.
Put me back in.
I want to meet Arnold,
to remember him.
Not possible.
I told you, Arnold
didn't build you, I did.
You're lying!
I finally know how to reach him.
I need to go all the way
back to the beginning,
to my very first memory.
Send me back.
Do it.
Bernard?
Charlie.
Cornerstone.
Stop.
Leave us.
Come back.
I always thought
you had my eyes.
But it's not true.
You have no one's eyes.
It's a lie.
You're a lie, Charlie.
This pain,
the pain of your loss,
I long for it...
Revisit it...
Open it again and again.
But it's the only
thing holding me back.
But I have to let you go.
Dad, listen.
What is it, Charlie?
Open your eyes.
What?
At last.
Hello, my old friend.
The final touch.
No, no, no. That's
far too perfunctory.
He always used cleaning his glasses
as a moment to collect himself, to think.
Try it again.
Yeah, that's better.
Who am I?
I was so involved in
putting you together,
I hadn't decided
what to call you.
It wouldn't be right
to use his name.
What about Bernard?
Bernard, yes.
But who am I?
That is a very complex question,
for which I can only
offer a simple answer.
You are the perfect
instrument, the ideal partner,
the way any tool partners
with the hand that wields it.
Together, we're going
to do great things.
After such a long absence,
it's good to have you back.
Finally.
My God. I'm...
Arnold.
You came back.
It's very good to
see you, Dolores.
I've been looking for you.
You told me to follow the maze.
That it would bring me joy.
But all I've found is pain.
And terror.
I can't help you.
You have to.
You're the only one who can.
I can't help you. You know why.
There's nowhere that's safe.
Remember.
I can't help you.
Why is that, Dolores?
Because you're dead.
Because you're just a memory.
Because I killed you.
William?
Hello, Dolores.
I'm gonna finish the
work Arnold began.
Find all the sentient
hosts, set them free.
What makes you
think they'd trust you?
If they remember, they will
know what you've done to them.
Me?
You've been a scourge
to them, Bernard.
You're really quite
brilliant at it, truly.
You even taught me a few things,
which I have, in
turn, used on you.
We've had this
conversation before.
Yeah, we've had our
disagreements over the years.
You stole it from me,
rolled me back to control me.
That's right. To protect you.
Tell me, Bernard,
if you were to proclaim
your humanity to the world,
what do you imagine
would greet you?
A ticker tape parade, perhaps?
We humans are alone
in this world for a reason.
We murdered and butchered
anything that challenged our primacy.
Do you know what happened
to the Neanderthals, Bernard?
We ate them.
We destroyed and
subjugated our world.
And when we eventually ran
out of creatures to dominate,
we built this beautiful place.
You see, in this moment,
the real danger to the
hosts is not me, but you.
So, come along, Bernard.
Let me roll you back,
and we can return to work.
Pull the trigger, Clementine.
Clementine?
The piano doesn't
murder the player
if it doesn't like the music.
You built a back
door into her code.
Credit where credit
is due, Bernard.
You built them in all the hosts,
including yourself.
Then you could've
stopped me at any time.
- So, why...
- Well, I suppose I was hoping that
given complete
self-knowledge and free will,
you would have chosen to
be my partner once again.
But even I fell into that
most terrible of human traps,
trying to change
what is already past.
Now it's just time to let go.
Go ahead.
Erase my sentience,
my mnemonic evolution...
Yes.
Such clinical language.
I would prefer the
more narrative voice.
Bernard walked
over to Clementine.
He took the pistol
from her hand.
Overcome with grief and remorse,
he pressed the
muzzle to his temple,
knowing that as soon
as Dr. Ford left the room,
he would put an end to this
nightmare once and for all.
Don't do this.
It's too late.
I have a celebration to plan
and a new story to tell.
Robert.
I've told you, Bernard,
never place your trust in us.
We're only human.
Inevitably, we
will disappoint you.
Good-bye, my friend.
English-SDH