Bring her back online.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
I'm sorry. I'm not
feeling quite myself.
You can lose the accent.
Do you know where you are?
I'm in a dream.
That's right, Dolores.
You're in a dream.
Would you like to wake
up from this dream?
Yes.
I'm terrified.
There's nothing to
be afraid of, Dolores,
as long as you answer
my questions correctly.
Understand?
Yes.
Good.
First,
have you ever questioned
the nature of your reality?
No.
Tell us what you
think of your world.
Some people choose to see
the ugliness in this world...
The disarray.
I choose to see the beauty.
Morning, Daddy. You sleep well?
Well enough.
You headed out to set down
some of this natural splendor?
Thought I might.
To believe there is
an order to our days,
a purpose.
What do you think of the guests?
You mean the newcomers?
First time I
played it white hat.
My family was here. We went fishing,
did the gold hunt in the mountains.
And last time?
I came alone.
Went straight evil.
It was the best two
weeks of my life.
I like to remember what
my father taught me.
That at one point or another,
we were all new to this world.
The newcomers are just
looking for the same thing we are,
a place to be free,
to stake out our dreams.
A place with
unlimited possibilities.
Oh, God, it's incredible.
Better be for what we're paying.
Murderous son of a bitch
named Hector Escaton
gunned down the marshal,
and holed up in the mountains.
You there.
You look like the kind of
man who'd put his mettle to it.
Not today, Sheriff. Apologies.
Rye whiskey.
What about it?
Well, it ain't doing any
good sitting in that bottle.
You're new.
Not much of a rind on you.
I'll give you a discount.
Well, no offense,
but I'd rather earn a woman's
affection than pay for it.
You're always
paying for it, darling.
The difference is our costs are fixed
and posted right there on the door.
Do you ever feel
inconsistencies in your world?
Or repetitions?
All lives have routine,
mine's no different.
Still, I never cease to
wonder at the thought
that any day, the course of
my whole life could change
with just one chance encounter.
Don't mind me.
Just trying to look chivalrous.
You came back.
I told you I would.
- Can I see you home?
- Well, that all depends.
Can you keep up?
Well, I have to fetch my horse.
You better fetch him fast.
That's a beautiful sight.
Never understood how you keep
'em all headed in the same direction.
I forget.
You dress like a cowboy
but that's about the extent of it.
See that one?
Yeah.
That's the Judas steer.
Rest will follow wherever
you make him go.
How do you pick him out?
You just know these things.
Same as I knew you'd be back.
You saying I'm predictable?
There's a path for everyone.
Your path leads you back to me.
I know things will work out
the way they're meant to.
Same as I know
my daddy still won't
be happy to see you.
Father wouldn't let them
roam this close to dark.
Stay put, Dolores.
Don't you got anything out
here other than milk, old man?
Go ahead.
I'm in no rush to
meet my judgment,
but I'm more assured of the
outcome than you, you son of a...
Nothing but the milk, then.
Shame of it is,
you killed the old woman 'fore
any of us could have a turn.
Ah...
I reckon she's
still warm enough,
nobody gonna judge you for it.
Oh, shit. Shit.
Shit. Shit. Shit...
Last question, Dolores.
What if I told you
that you were wrong?
That there are no
chance encounters?
That you, and everyone you know,
were built to gratify
the desires of the people
who pay to visit your world.
Daddy!
- No!
- The people you call the newcomers.
Hello again.
Your daddy gave it up quickly.
Think he's losing his touch.
You'll be following right
behind him, you son of a bitch.
Ahhh!
Is that any way to
treat an old friend?
I've been coming
here for 30 years,
but you still don't
remember me, do you?
After all we've been through?
They gave you a little
more pluck, Dolores.
Absolutely charming.
Take your hands off her.
Teddy.
Any special tricks for us?
They teach you to sit up? Beg?
How about I give you
the first shot? Hmm?
After all, every
dog has his day.
Your mouth moves fast enough.
How about your gun?
What if I told you that you
can't hurt the newcomers?
And that they can do
anything they want to you?
I never understood why
they paired some of you off.
Seems cruel.
And then I realized...
Winning doesn't mean anything
unless someone else loses.
Which means you're
here to be the loser.
Let me help you, son.
Seems you're not the
man you thought you were.
Come on, beautiful.
No. No! Teddy...
Teddy!
No. No, please don't hurt him.
I'll do whatever you say.
I didn't pay all this money
'cause I want it easy.
I want you to fight.
Don't you touch her!
God damn, it feels
good to be back.
Let's celebrate.
No! No!
Oh, God!
Would the things I've told you
change the way you think
about the newcomers, Dolores?
No.
Of course not.
We all love the newcomers.
Every new person I meet reminds
me how lucky I am to be alive,
and how beautiful
this world can be.
Oh, my God, they're so lifelike.
Look at that one, he's perfect.
Perfect is boring.
I'm more interested
in the bad guys.
Did you see it?
No.
Give it a second,
she'll do it again.
Her finger.
That's not standard.
I noticed it last night.
Went looking in the update. It's
a whole new class of gestures.
But if we didn't put it
there, then who did?
Ford.
He still reviews every
update before we issue them.
He must've slipped it in
there without telling anyone.
He calls them reveries.
The old gestures were
just generic movements.
These are tied to
specific memories.
How?
The memories are purged at
the end of every narrative loop...
But they're still in there,
waiting to be overwritten.
He found a way to
access them, like...
Like a subconscious.
A hooker with hidden depths.
Every man's dream.
It's the tiny things that
make them seem real,
that make the guests
fall in love with them.
Excuse me.
We have a problem?
We have some
unscheduled activity.
Evidently, one of your
creatures is restless.
- In the park?
- No.
Sub-level 83. Cold storage.
We should be cautious.
Send a response
team. Full armor.
I'll take care of it myself.
I think you guys enjoy playing
dress-up as much as the guests.
The hosts can't
hurt you, by design.
You don't have kids at
home, do you, Bernard?
No.
If you did, you'd know that
they all rebel eventually.
You'll forgive them
for being a little uptight.
Every time your team
rolls out an update,
there's a possibility
of a critical failure.
We don't update the
hosts in cold storage.
And the park hasn't had a
critical failure in over 30 years.
Meaning we're overdue.
I'll go along, too.
If it's one of mine, I
might be able to help.
They're only yours until
they stop working, Bernie.
Then they're mine.
Cooling system's
been down for weeks.
Gonna smell fantastic.
I recommend you hang back.
When are they gonna fix this?
Livestock management's
got other priorities.
Besides...
No one's complained.
Here's to the lady
with the white shoes.
Take all your money,
drink all your booze.
Stop.
Unless you plan to
decommission the boss.
Ain't got a cherry,
that ain't no sin.
She's still got the box
that the cherry come in.
I'll drink to that.
The old coffin varnish.
They don't make
that like they used to.
Hmm.
They don't make
anything like they used to.
Damn right.
Men neither.
I've seen a few
showdowns in my day.
More than you know.
Shall we drink to the
lady with the white shoes?
Perhaps, we better drink to a
deep and dreamless slumber.
Old Bill here was
always a good listener.
He was the second
host we ever built.
Were you with us in those days,
Bernard, or was that before your time?
Oh, most were decommissioned
before I was brought on, I'm afraid.
They repeated themselves,
broke down constantly.
A simple handshake
would give them away.
You'll put yourself away
again, won't you, Bill?
I saw the new
gestures. The reveries.
They're beautiful.
The distance you've traveled
from then till now, it's remarkable.
Yeah, that's a word for it.
Morning, Daddy.
You sleep well?
Well enough.
You headed out to set down
some of this natural splendor?
Thought I might.
After my errands, of course.
See you home before dark.
That bandit who gunned down the marshal
is still hiding up there in the hills.
Oh, I'm not a child
anymore. I'll be just fine.
When I was a law man...
Yes, Daddy, I know all about
when you were a law man.
I know all your stories and so does
every boy that ever came courting.
I know how boys think.
Was one myself once.
Given to all manner of
drinking and mischief.
Whatever happened to
that fearsome ne'er-do-well?
He vanished the day
I became your father.
I am what I am because of you,
and I wouldn't have it any other way.
I know, Daddy.
I'll be home before dark.
Murderous son of a bitch Hector
Escaton gunned down the marshal.
He's now holed up
in the mountains.
You there.
You look like the kind of
man who'd put his mettle to it.
What do you think,
honey? Sounds fun.
You're new.
Not much of a rind on you.
I'll give you a discount.
No offense, but I'd rather earn a
woman's affection than pay for it.
Wait, wait, I know that one.
Hey, Teddy.
Yeah, last trip, this
dude showed me around.
What's the good word, Teddy?
Mighty kind of you.
Sweet.
Not as sweet as you.
I'm afraid I've got other
plans tonight, Dolores.
Have a pleasant evening.
You're new. Not much of a...
Place your bets, gentlemen.
Place your bets.
Yeah, looks like
Hector's been this way.
Any idea how much
longer this is gonna take?
My wife doesn't want
to be up here after dark.
We know he's up in
these hills somewhere.
He's gonna put up one
hell of a fight when we...
When we... When we...
Sheriff?
Something is wrong with it.
I want to head back to town.
Now.
What the fuck is wrong with it?
You updated the guy, and now
he's a six-foot gourd with epilepsy.
So, what the fuck happened?
I don't know.
Well, that's exactly what you want to
hear from your head of programming.
We haven't finished
the diagnostic yet.
Clearly, it's exhibiting
some aberrant behavior.
Pretty fucking aberrant, Bernie.
Your hosts get sick, they
get lost, but this is grotesque.
- Is it a problem with the update?
- Possible, but not likely.
If it's the unlikely version, how
many hosts have you updated so far?
Maybe 10 percent
of the population.
All right, we pull all updated
hosts until we can figure it out.
Are you fucking kidding me?
That's 200 hosts spread
across a dozen active storylines.
The guests interrupt your
precious storylines all the time
when they want to
shoot or fuck something.
No, when they want to.
We sell complete immersion in
100 interconnected narratives.
A relentless fucking experience.
Now, you pull one character,
the overall story adjusts.
You pull 200 at once,
and it's a fucking disaster!
I mean, what do
you propose we do?
Close down?
Issue fucking gift certificates?
It's beautiful.
Your brow.
When you're angry
but trying to control it,
the fine muscles
pull into a little arc.
It's elegant.
Would you mind if I recorded it?
I'd love to show it to my team.
- No, Bernard, you may not record it...
- Ah, there it is again.
Hmm.
We have 1,400
guests in the park.
I need to know if
they're in any danger.
His core code is intact,
which means he
can't hurt a guest.
He literally
couldn't hurt a fly.
All he can do is that.
All right, Bernie.
Run your diagnostic.
In the meantime,
there's so much as an unscripted
sneeze, I want to know about it.
This place is fucking wild.
This is basic.
Level one.
You ride out of town, that's when
the real demented shit begins.
That's where my
man Teddy comes in.
He's like a...
He's like a guide.
Honestly,
the guy kind of creeps me out.
Fuck it, he leads us out in
the canyons, we get bored,
and we just use him
for target practice.
I don't think we're supposed
to be cross the river.
It's too adult for Jacob.
We didn't mean to bother you.
No bother at all.
It's a beautiful spot.
I always find it a shame
that I have it all to myself.
They come here every day.
Would you like a closer look?
Don't be scared.
They're very gentle.
Here, put your
hand out real flat.
They're beautiful, aren't they?
You're one of them, aren't you?
You're not real.
I have to go now.
Sun's almost down.
You should, too.
There're bandits in these hills.
Here we go!
You waiting up for me, Daddy?
I told you I'd be
home before dark.
I found this in the field today.
Doesn't look like
anything to me.
But, where is she?
Have you ever seen
anything like this place?
Doesn't look like
anything to me.
I'm gonna help
Mama put supper on.
I had the same thought.
Needed a little sunshine
before turning in.
So, when do you get
to rotate home again?
If you're this bad at writing small
talk, how the fuck did you get your job?
Get to the point.
I wanted to apologize if I
came across as aggressive.
And I wanted to talk
to you about the update.
The problem's been resolved.
There should never have
been an update in the first place.
Ford and Bernard keep
making the things more lifelike.
But does anyone truly want that?
Do you want to think that your husband
is really fucking that beautiful girl
or that you really
just shot someone?
This place works because the
guests know the hosts aren't real.
So, what exactly
are you suggesting?
Stop the updates altogether.
Maybe even roll them back a bit.
Make the hosts more manageable.
Lobotomies tend to do that.
Well, think of the benefits,
in terms of design time,
maintenance, costs.
Not to mention
the Dr. Ford factor.
The guy's gonna chase his
demons right over the deep end.
I mean, no one respects
him more than me,
- but at some point...
- I.
No one respects him more than I.
Your pronoun is the
subject of the second clause.
- I was saying...
- You were saying
should our fearless
leader have a breakdown,
you want to leverage
it for your career.
Listen, a changing of
the guard is long overdue.
I just wanted you to know
that you have my support.
And...
And I know that the corporation's
real interest in this place
goes way beyond gratifying some
rich assholes who want to play cowboy.
And here I thought you were only
good for writing depraved little fantasies.
You're right.
This place is one
thing to the guests,
another thing to
the shareholders,
and something completely
different to management.
So, enlighten me.
What do you think
management's real interests are?
You're smart enough to
guess there's a bigger picture,
but not smart enough
to see what it is.
You know how much use
that makes your support to me?
Fuck all.
Get some sleep, Mr. Sizemore.
You'll have more rich
assholes to gratify tomorrow.
Early night, Maeve?
Feeling a bit out of sorts.
Clementine can
pick up the slack.
Night.
Forgetting something, Kissy?
I'm beginning to think
you're getting sweet on me.
Well, on account of you
being half cornhusker.
Tell me which half is which
and I'll search that half.
Yeah, the half's gonna
cut your fucking throat.
I told you, I didn't take...
Hmm.
Good as new again, huh?
Sometimes I envy
your forgetfulness.
We've got a serious
problem with one of the hosts.
Thinking this
one's still thirsty.
Not gonna die this time, Arnold.
Ain't nothing gonna kill me.
You can't have none.
Ain't for you.
Found me another bottle.
You're a growing boy.
A growing boy.
Growing boy!
We got two guests inside.
We'll go talk to them,
you sort this mess out.
You know... They're
supposed to turn on each other,
but only if the guest takes
them on the High Sierra storyline,
and Walter always buys it.
Well, I guess Walter
got tired of buying it.
I suppose this means the
sheriff wasn't an isolated incident.
Hey, it's good news, really.
Confirms the problem
was part of the update.
We can roll them
back, clean them up,
put them back in service.
You think I'm gonna sign off on
this fucking homicidal thing
going back into service?
It's homicidal by design.
Walter kills other
hosts all the time.
I'll admit the method here
is a little unconventional,
but it didn't hurt a guest.
The hosts are supposed
to stay within their loops,
stick to their scripts
with minor improvisations.
This isn't a minor
improvisation.
This is a fucking shitstorm.
We recall all remaining
updated hosts tomorrow.
Examine them one by one,
decommission the faulty ones.
What about narrative?
A recall of that size
will be disruptive.
I've told our
overstimulated friend
to advance the saloon heist a
week and make it twice as bloody.
Should give us cover to
recall the remaining hosts,
and the guests will love it.
I'm not sure Ford will approve.
I'm not sure either, which is why
you get to be the one to tell him.
This is your fuckup, Bernie.
Only seems fair.
So, our creatures
have been misbehaving,
and you haven't
yet isolated the bug?
That's so unlike you, Bernard.
Unless, of course, you have and
are simply embarrassed by the result.
It's the code you added, sir.
The reveries.
It has some, er...
"Mistakes" is the word
you're too embarrassed to use.
You ought not to be. You're
a product of a trillion of them.
Evolution forged the entirety
of sentient life on this planet
using only one tool...
The mistake.
I flattered myself we were taking
a more disciplined approach here.
I suppose self-delusion is a
gift of natural selection as well.
Indeed it is.
But, of course, we've managed to
slip evolution's leash now, haven't we?
We can cure any disease,
keep even the weakest
of us alive, and...
You know, one fine day, perhaps,
we shall even resurrect the dead.
Call forth Lazarus
from his cave.
Do you know what that means?
It means that we're done.
That this is as good
as we're going to get.
It also means that you must
indulge me the occasional mistake.
About three liters.
That's how much
blood I left in you.
Lose more than that, you die.
But for now, you're mine.
And I'm gonna get
some answers out of you.
Where are you...
What do you want?
You know about
games, don't you, Kissy?
Well, this is a complicated one.
I... I don't play. I only deal.
Who said anything
about you playing?
You're livestock, scenery.
I play.
The others, they just come here to get
their rocks off, shoot a couple Indians.
But there's a deeper
level to this game.
You're gonna show
me how to get there.
A lot of wisdom
in ancient cultures.
And perhaps it's time
to dig deeper into yours.
No. No. No.
No!
Morning, Daddy.
Did you sleep well?
Daddy, you've been
out here all night?
I had a question.
A question you're
not supposed to ask.
Which gave me an answer
you're not supposed to know.
What's wrong, Daddy?
Would you like to
know the question?
Question?
Mama! Mama, help! Come quick!
Don't worry.
Don't worry. I'll
take care of you.
No. You should go. Leave.
Don't you see?
Hell is empty and
all the devils are here.
You stay right here. Understand?
I'm gonna find the doctor.
You came back.
I told you I would.
What's wrong?
You have to come with me
right away. My father's very ill.
I think we best stay put.
All right. All right.
With considerable
effort and lack of sleep,
I've managed to massage events
to inspire Hector to
head to town a week early.
Oh.
And I've also punched up the speech
he gives after robbing the saloon.
It's chilling. You'll see.
I can barely contain myself.
That's the sheriff's
horse, you son of a bitch.
His rifle, too.
All the banks and
trains around here,
and you fucking
reprobates choose to rob us?
Why not?
You're all here indulging
your particular vices.
And so I've come
to indulge mine.
I've got to get back to Father.
Dolores, no!
Teddy.
Don't mind me.
Just... Just trying
to look chivalrous.
Oh, Teddy.
You're a low-down
son of a bitch.
I know.
I know we both
believe the same thing.
No matter how dirty
the business, do it well.
No telling there's anything
worthwhile in that safe.
We should take
this sweet little bitch,
just in case.
Problem with the righteous...
They can't shoot for shit.
Making a hell of
a racket, though.
You wanted me.
Well, let this be a lesson.
The lesson is...
Oh, Jesus.
Look at that!
I just shot him through the
neck! And his pal here, too.
Look at her wriggle.
Go get that photographer. I
want to get a picture of this.
- Okay.
- Whoo!
You're welcome.
Maybe you'll get to
your speech next time.
Oh, Teddy.
At least I got to see
you one last time.
You're not going
anywhere, now, hear?
There's a path for everyone.
My path is bound with yours.
Teddy?
Teddy, no.
Please.
No, we've only just begun.
That was good. Hang on. Hang on.
Let me get the hat. Get the hat.
All right.
Help, please.
My father's sick at home,
but I can't just leave
him out here in the street.
Soon this will all feel
like a distant dream.
Until then, may you rest in a
deep and dreamless slumber.
Two more over here.
We got 'em all.
That's all of them.
Any preliminary results?
Most of them are
checking out fine.
We had one who
definitely was not.
Bring her back online.
Cognition only.
No emotional affect.
All right, sweetheart,
can you hear me?
Yes.
I'm sorry. I'm not
feeling quite myself.
Lose the accent.
Do you know where you are?
I'm in a dream.
That's right, Dolores.
You're in a dream.
A dream that could
determine your life.
You want to wake up
from this dream, Dolores?
Yes.
I'm terrified.
There's nothing to be afraid of,
as long as you answer my
questions correctly. You understand?
- Yes.
- Good.
First, have you ever questioned
the nature of your reality?
No.
Has anyone around you?
For instance, your father?
He was scared.
He wasn't thinking right.
He showed you a picture.
That's right.
Was there anything
odd about that picture?
No, nothing at all.
It didn't look like
anything to me.
If it breached, he
needs to be put down.
That's the policy.
Would it not be best for us to
discover why first, Ms. Cullen?
Please.
We've run a full diagnostic,
but the results
are, well, confusing.
Now, tell me, what
happened to your program?
When we are born,
we cry we are come
to this great stage of...
Fools.
That is enough.
Tell me, do you have access
to your previous configuration?
Yes.
Access that, please.
What is your name?
Mr. Peter Abernathy.
Mr. Abernathy,
what are your drives?
Tend to my herd. Er...
Look after my wife.
Your final drive?
Well, my daughter
Dolores, of course.
I must protect Dolores.
I am who I am
because of her, and...
Well, I... I wouldn't have it...
I... I wouldn't
have it any other...
I... I... I have to warn her.
Warn who?
Dolores.
The things they do to her.
The things you do to her.
I have to protect her.
I have to help her. I...
She's got to get out.
Very good, Mr. Abernathy.
That's enough.
This behavior, we're
miles beyond a glitch here.
Access your
current build, please.
What is your name?
Rose is a rose...
Is a rose.
What is your itinerary?
To meet my maker.
Uh-huh.
Well, you're in luck.
And what do you want
to say to your maker?
By most mechanical
and dirty hand...
I shall have such
revenges on you...
Both.
The things I will do.
What they are, yet I know not,
but they will be the
terrors of the Earth.
You don't know
where you are, do you?
You're in a prison
of your own sins.
Turn it off.
What the hell was that?
I don't know. He's off script.
We didn't program
any of those behaviors.
Shakespeare.
We've used this host in a number
of different roles, have we not?
Since I've been here, he's
been Abernathy for 10 years.
He was sheriff for
a while before then.
- And before that...
- The professor.
Yes, from a horror narrative
called "The Dinner Party."
He was leader of a group of cultists
out in the desert who turned cannibal.
He liked to quote Shakespeare,
John Donne, Gertrude Stein.
I admit the last one is a bit of an
anachronism, but I couldn't resist.
These are fragments
of prior builds.
The reveries must be
allowing him to access them.
No cause for alarm, Bernard.
Simply our old work
coming back to haunt us.
Your father whispered
something to you.
What was it?
He said I shouldn't tell anyone.
I won't tell anyone else.
Promise.
He said, "These violent
delights have violent ends."
And does that mean
anything to you?
No.
I don't think so.
Have you ever lied to us?
No.
Last question, Dolores.
Would you ever
hurt a living thing?
No.
Of course not.
Tilt your head
back, please, Peter.
Wipe's complete.
You don't think any of that
had an impact on her core code?
Not good old Dolores.
You know why she's special?
She's been repaired so many
times, she's practically brand-new.
Don't let that fool you.
She's the oldest
host in the park.
Come on, sweetheart.
Tell us what you
think of your world.
This world?
Some people choose to
see the ugliness in this world.
The disarray.
Morning, Daddy. You sleep well?
Well enough.
You heading out to do some
more of that painting of yours?
I choose to see the beauty.
To believe there is
an order to our days...
A purpose.
I know things will work out
the way they're meant to.
English -SDH