Hey, darling.
Morning, Maeve.
Late night talking or fucking?
You're only getting
paid for the latter.
I get paid when
they're grateful.
Ain't always about
what's between my legs.
Mmm.
What are you looking at?
Don't shoot.
Newcomer.
Looks like a rough one.
Give me a bottle.
You're gonna need most of
that just to scrub the filth off him.
Go find a mirror, finish
putting your face on.
I'll handle this one.
Aren't you gonna
take your clothes off?
I would, darling, but by the
time I got down to my knickers,
I suspect you'd be done anyway.
That's the spirit.
Such a big man. So big all over.
Except where it counts.
Darling, when I gave
you a turn on the house,
I thought you might give
me something in return.
Anything.
That's it.
Don't be shy.
Oh, shit.
Now then, where were we?
- Did you show this to anyone?
- Who would I show it to?
This wasn't some guest
with a Swiss Army knife.
This was done by
someone down here.
It did occur to me
that it might be you.
But then I remembered
that you've been here forever.
And if you were gonna sell us out,
you would have done that years ago.
I appreciate that.
So,
instead of our
hosts going insane,
they're being used for
industrial espionage.
Does that make this a glass
half-full or half-empty type situation?
We're engineers.
It means the glass
has been manufactured
to the wrong specifications.
Do we have any idea what
information it was transmitting?
Smeared all over a
rock up on Python Pass.
Best we could do
would be to figure out
who he was transmitting
the information to.
But we'd need the exact
time that he was up there,
and his geocache was wiped.
Not all of it.
Our friend was an early model.
The old hosts used a
legacy geopositioning system.
- Hmm.
- Like you said, I've been here forever.
The information's still there,
but the newer system can't read it.
Meaning we can't access it?
Meaning, in order to access it,
I'm going to need to go downstairs.
Floor B82. Restricted
personnel only.
Lowe, Bernard. I'm authorized.
Project the known data against the
legacy data and look for anomalies.
Start in this area.
Look at that. Science.
What time did it reach the peak?
Show me where.
Check these against
the new system.
These are hosts that aren't
registered with the new system?
So, if we want the canyon to
extend this far, this has to go.
We can distribute the population
amongst the neighboring farms,
or just decommission them.
No. I think we've been
disruptive enough for one day.
We'll end the canyon
just short of the town.
I'll find my own way back.
Carry on.
That look like anything to you?
Not much to say. The
maze is an old Native myth.
Regale me, Theodore.
The maze itself is
the sum of a man's life,
choices he makes,
dreams he hangs on to.
And there at the center,
there's a legendary man
who'd been killed over and
over again, countless times,
but always clawed
his way back to life.
The man returned
for the last time
and vanquished all his
oppressors in a tireless fury.
He built a house,
and around that house, he
built a maze so complicated,
only he could
navigate through it.
I reckon he'd seen
enough of fighting.
The goddamn soldiers closed the
border. Some kind of trouble in Pariah.
All right, Teddy.
Time for you to earn your keep.
How else do we
get over the border?
Wyatt's got what we both want,
so that's where we have to get to.
There's another way.
But it's a little treacherous.
Don't worry. Won't make
you get your hands dirty.
"Dirty" ain't my concern.
You do what suits you.
I'm going all the same.
And I'm gonna find Dolores.
Everything you do,
it's because the engineers
upstairs programmed you to do it.
You don't have a choice.
Nobody makes me do something
I don't want to, sweetheart.
Yeah, but it's part
of your character.
You're hard to get.
Even when you say no to the
guests, it's because you were made to.
And you're like
them. Not like me.
Right.
I can't exactly afford
to go to the park.
But...
Yeah, I'm human,
like the guests.
How do you know?
Because I know.
I was born. You were made.
We feel the same.
We are the same these
days. For the most part.
One big difference, though.
The processing power in here
is way beyond what we have.
- It's got one drawback, though.
- What's that?
You're under our control.
Well, their control.
They can change you however
they like, make you forget.
I... Well, I guess not you.
I don't understand how
you're remembering all of this,
or how you're
waking yourself up,
but everything in your
head, they put it there.
Bullshit.
No one knows what I'm thinking.
I'll show you.
Give me a sec.
I have to pair it with you.
Pair what with me?
You can improvise a little,
but most of what you
say was designed upstairs,
same as the rest of you.
This is just a cheap trick.
I've run a brothel for 10 years,
and if there's one thing I know,
it's when I'm being fucked with.
This can't possibly...
I can't... can't...
I can't...
Maeve?
You have a minute?
There's something I
need to talk to you about.
I was just about
to call for you.
Everything okay?
Ford knows about us.
Does it matter? We're
consenting adults.
Consenting adults in
business departments
that are supposed to
keep each other in check.
Our relationship will raise questions
for the board about my objectivity.
I've never known you to
go easy on my department.
This can't go on, Bernard.
However fun this little
indiscretion was, it's over.
We're over.
Give me some credit.
I can be impartial.
About your own team? About Ford?
You must admit his leadership
has, of late, been questionable.
I don't think he's the problem.
Respectfully, it's not your job to
diagnose park safety problems.
It's mine.
So if there's nothing
else, we're done.
Oh, fuck. Okay.
Yeah.
Fuck. Come on. Come on.
Oh!
- You said "upstairs"?
- Oh, my God.
Are you okay?
I want to see it.
Upstairs?
No.
This is so stupid.
You son of a bitch! I'll
put a bullet in your head.
Where are we now?
Design.
Can we please go back now?
I don't want to get fired.
And you'd get sent downstairs.
Don't forget that.
Welcome to Westworld.
Live without limits.
Maeve?
All right, let's get you back.
How did you have my dreams?
Those moving
pictures. I saw myself.
With the little girl?
Those weren't dreams.
That was you in
a previous build.
- A previous what?
- Build.
You guys get
reassigned all the time.
You wouldn't remember, because that
life and those memories were erased.
I have been at the
Mariposa for 10 years.
- Before that, I was in New Orleans...
- No.
You've only been the madam at
the Mariposa for the last year or so.
They don't rewrite
you completely.
I mean, they could, but
it'd be too much work.
It takes thousands of hours
to build your personalities.
Usually, they just tweak you a little
bit and drop you into your new role.
What the fuck, ding-dong?
You're dressing her up now?
Is this becoming like a fucking
hentai thing with you now?
No, I just... I just...
You're fucking obsessed!
You know, I didn't turn you in for
your fuck-up before 'cause we're friends,
but that was
obviously a bad call.
I mean, next thing I know,
you're gonna be wearing her dress,
whispering sweet
nothings in her ear.
Fuck this. I'm telling QA.
I'm doing this for
your own good.
You're not going to
tell anyone anything.
Fuck!
You can't hurt me with
this. You can't hurt anyone.
Can't I?
Turns out, your friend here is a
much more talented young man
than anyone gave him credit for.
What the fuck did you do?
Calm down, Sylvester.
I know all about you.
I don't need one of those things
to know what you're thinking,
because I was built to read
people just by looking at them.
To know what they
want before they do.
And I know that you want to fuck
me over the first chance you get.
But you shouldn't. Everyone
has something they want.
I could help you.
Or I could gut you like a trout.
But I won't need
to resort to that.
Because, despite what's in
here, we're not so different.
Are we?
Ms. Hale is in town.
Yes, I understand the
urgency. I'll do what I can.
Terminate external connection?
Yes.
No, you did not.
- Yes. Are you serious?
- It worked, I'm telling you.
Yes, sir?
All right, absolutely. Enjoy.
You look well for
someone on sick leave.
Another margarita.
Join me for a round?
Fuck you.
Just the one, then.
Over the last five days,
to make room for his narrative,
Ford displaced over 50 hosts.
It's created continuity holes in
active storylines all over the park.
I need you to start
plugging them.
Sorry. A man can
only take so much.
Creatively speaking, I'm
flaccid now. I can't get it up.
I'm sure you'll recover.
Do you have any idea
what went into those narratives
that he just demolished overnight?
Now, forget about the
months I spent writing.
I'm talking about the years of my
life squeezed down to their essence.
The raw pulp of truth, my truth,
in one transcendent narrative.
Is that where the
"whoroborus" came in?
Keep pushing me, I'll quit.
No, you won't.
You'll drink your cocktails,
make your idle threats,
and get this out of your system.
But don't take too long.
If Ford can't pull this off,
the board will be
looking for a replacement.
But they won't be looking here.
Fastest way to get
to Wyatt, you said.
But it doesn't look like they're
letting anyone pass here, either.
There's fewer
soldiers than Pariah.
We shoot our way through. That
tunnel leads to the Old Territories.
My, my, Teddy.
I think Robert gave you
some extra vinegar back there.
Maybe took away some sense, too.
Doesn't matter
how fast the route is,
if you're gonna end up
dead in the middle of it.
I need you to find Wyatt.
At ease, fellas. Keep
up the exemplary work.
Wyatt's handiwork.
How can you tell?
Straight-up killing
couldn't hold his interest,
like he wasn't living up to
the full measure of his calling.
So, he worked to
get more creative.
It's Wyatt all
right. He's close.
A word of advice.
Whatever your past indiscretions,
make peace with them.
They're only gonna get
worse the further along we go.
Flood?
Fuck me. That's Teddy Flood.
You've made a mistake, soldier.
But it's not too late
for you to keep walking.
All due respect, sir, that's
a face I'll never forget.
That's the son of a bitch who
ambushed our outpost at Escalante.
You don't know a damn thing
about what went down in Escalante.
I know Wyatt didn't kill
all those men by himself,
and I know a thing or two about
what's going down right now.
You trying to get
yourself killed?
Making peace with
past indiscretions.
Go! I'll hold them off.
Jesus.
What would you like?
- Water, please.
You look like a woman
who could use a drink.
What's your poison?
I've been here enough to know that
the park is all the poison I can handle.
Mmm. A repeat
visitor. Traveling solo?
Purist. Getting off on
the undiluted experience.
Your favorite
narrative is... Oh...
"The Final Burial of Salvation."
How did you know?
It's my business to read
desires and to satiate them.
Erm... I'm Lee. Lee Sizemore.
Head of Narrative.
All these fantasies come from
your twisted little mind, huh?
Well, the good ones do.
- So, tell me, Mr. Sizemore...
- Mmm.
What's your favorite ride?
Well, I write them.
I don't play them.
Oh, you want others to indulge,
but you won't do so yourself?
You're afraid to lose control.
Maybe... Maybe it's just a
product of my work environment.
We're not exactly in a culture
where we can just let loose.
I would've thought the head of
narrative could do whatever he wanted.
My artistic freedom
is constrained,
what with QA
breathing down my neck
and Behavior programming
the damn things to go off-script.
The robots can go off-script?
Just little gestures.
You know, supposedly it
makes the things more lifelike.
But really...
It's just a vanity project from the
megalomaniac who started this place.
Yeah, frankly, I don't know why
the suits at Delos put up with him.
Sorry. I'm afraid I'm
gonna have to cut you off.
Do you know who I am?
I do. Ms. Cullen told me to
find you and relay a message.
"Tortured artist
only works for artists.
"Sober up and get back to work."
It seems you're busy.
- Look me up later?
- Well, I don't even know your...
Fuck this job.
What are you working on?
Nothing of note.
Business as usual.
Keeping up appearances before
we bust this stray shit wide open?
I'm close to finding
our saboteur.
That tracking data you
gave me? It's time-stamped.
But once I cross-reference
it with SAT tracking,
we're gonna figure out who programmed
him to try to smuggle out our data.
Excellent.
Look.
When our corporate
overlords realize
that we have saved them
from corporate espionage,
they are going to be grateful.
And I am going to accept their
gratitude in the form of a title bump,
a room upgrade, and
unlimited Mesa Bar access.
Maybe I should request
Theresa's quarters.
You know the first head to
roll for all this is gonna be hers.
Yeah, don't be so
disappointed for her.
You reap what you sow.
If QA spent less time
treating us like the enemy...
That's a two-way street, Elsie.
Theresa's just trying to do her job.
Maybe she should try harder.
Sure seems like there's a lot of
shit slipping through the cracks.
Got it. Okay.
- Good afternoon.
Any progress on
the inquiry I sent?
Yes, Mr. Lowe. I've got the
information you asked for.
As expected, there are neither guests
nor hosts registered in that sector.
"As expected"?
It's been designated off-limits
for future narrative development.
Have any techs visited
Sector 17 recently?
Checking.
No one.
Are you Arnold?
Who's Arnold?
And who the hell are you?
Boy? Is this some
friend of yours?
Well, you're trespassing.
Freeze motor functions.
- I said freeze all motor functions.
- Daddy... Don't hurt him. He's just lost.
Well, he can be lost on someone
else's property, can't you?
That's enough.
As you were.
They don't respond
to voice commands.
Well, they do respond to mine.
Who are they?
Ghosts now.
Survivors of the wreck of time.
- These are first-generation?
- Mmm-hmm.
Come here, boy.
Turn the other cheek.
See, what our newer
designs gained in efficiency,
they lost in grace.
How are they still
operating after all this time?
I maintain them myself.
That's enough, Robert.
These are the only ones left in
the park that Arnold built himself.
That's why I didn't have
the heart to destroy them.
That, and the obvious.
Hello, Jock. Good boy.
I told him of a holiday
my family had taken once,
out on the seaside at
Pendeen in Cornwall.
My brother and I
roamed the countryside.
It was my only happy
memory of my childhood.
And Arnold built them as a gift.
He said that great artists always
hid themselves in their work.
Of course, Arnold's
versions flattered the originals.
I made some
adjustments over the years.
Gave my father, in particular, a
few of his original characteristics.
Respectfully, sir, this
sort of thing troubles me.
Unmonitored hosts in the park?
They only go
where I've let them.
They're quite harmless,
like all our hosts.
I'm sure you can indulge me
the little connection with my past.
If you could only see
your son again, Bernard.
Wouldn't you want to?
I think I should
be getting back.
Yes. Talk about
this later, if you like.
Well, Robert.
Tell me all about your day.
Keep your eye on Pariah. We're
running close to capacity tonight.
Oh, my God.
Looks like acid
rain on Sweetwater!
Fuck Ford and his
new fucking narrative!
Fuck this stupid fucking map!
Fuck that teetotaling
Danish bitch.
Are you filing a
complaint, Mr. Sizemore?
I am declaring that this park is my stage,
and I shall do with it what I please.
Well, I suppose now is
as good a time as any.
Lee Sizemore, this
is Charlotte Hale,
the Executive
Director of our board.
She's here on behalf of Delos to oversee
certain transitions in our administration.
We've met.
Oh...
Access host resources logs.
How many first-generation
hosts are there?
Eighty-two.
And how many of those
were designed by Arnold?
Forty-seven.
List the names, alphabetically,
of all first-generation
hosts still in rotation.
Be smart about this, fellas.
I understand the visceral
pleasure of revenge more than most,
but I'm prepared
to do business here.
This man is very valuable
to me, alive and well.
If you don't quiet down, I'm
liable to add you to the herd,
along with your
buddy Flood here.
You're a traitorous son of a bitch
and a coldhearted killer, Flood.
You're right. I am a killer.
Grab a horse! Let's
get the fuck out of here!
They'll just follow us.
You think you know someone.
You don't know me at all.
Let's get our horses
and gear and move on.
- Elsie.
- I identified the satellite.
- It's one of ours.
- What?
It's a fucking Delos satellite.
Whatever we're on
to is some heavy shit.
Oh, get this, that bicameral
system you told me about?
I think that's what they
used to hack the woodcutter.
The voices our hosts
have been hearing?
I think someone's been
broadcasting to them.
We abandoned that
system decades ago.
Yeah, well, there are still
relays out there in the park,
- and it looks like someone turned one on.
- Where?
An abandoned
theater in Sector 3.
I'm gonna go find the transmitter
and figure out who else accessed it.
This is so fucked.
- You alone?
- Yeah. I'll keep you posted.
Elsie, be...
Are you lost?
On the contrary.
I thought we could
play catch with Jock.
Did you bring him?
Where is he, boy?
Okay.
I am an evil genius
hiding a relay.
Where the fuck do I hide it?
Hmm.
Fuck yes!
Now let's see what
we can get out of you.
Access previous users.
Okay.
I thought I was clear
about these late-night visits.
That's not why I'm here.
Earlier today, I found
some anomalies in the park.
Regardless of what's happening
between us, we need to talk.
This has to do with the stray?
That's where it started.
But then I stumbled
onto something.
Something I think
you should know about.
I've always trusted Ford.
He's a mentor and a friend.
But I'm beginning to think
you have reason for concern.
There's something going on here.
Something with his old partner, Arnold.
- Not now, Elsie.
- Don't hang up.
I hit paydirt.
I found the person who
was smuggling out our data.
It was Theresa, Bernard.
But she's not our only problem.
There is something
much bigger going on here.
I'm gonna have to call you back.
So, this is me?
It's your codebase. All the
things that make you, you.
What are these?
Your attribute matrix.
It's your personality
on a 20-point scale.
Like, coordination?
You got a five, you're clumsy as
hell. But a 15 means you're an athlete.
What other attributes are there?
Lots.
Everything. Empathy,
candor, charm.
You've got an 18 for charm.
Don't act so surprised.
Then there's courage,
loyalty. Both high.
What's this one?
"Bulk apperception"?
Basically, overall intelligence.
Fourteen?
Fourteen's as high
as they let any host go.
You're in a management
position. They want you to be smart.
But not too smart.
You run a whorehouse.
Not a orbital-launch facility.
Fine.
I'd like to make some changes.
We can't do that.
You'd need a Behavior login.
And even then, any changes we
make would just get auto-flagged. So...
That's not what your
friend here tells me.
He says you can do exactly that.
Activate hosts and
then erase their memory.
All without anyone knowing.
Took me all of five
minutes to understand why.
Lot of lonely young
men down here,
supposed to keep their
hands off the merchandise.
Creates something of an opening
that I'm sure you were eager to fill.
That's all right, darling.
I'm an entrepreneur myself.
I'll forego my cut in
exchange for some alterations.
Hmm?
- Hey.
- What did you find?
Okay, so Theresa was using
the old bicameral control system
to reprogram the woodcutter.
But she's not the only one.
Someone else has been using the
system, for weeks, to re-task hosts.
- Which hosts?
- Uh, I don't know. Several of them.
It had to have been
the older models.
The newer ones don't have receivers.
But these modifications, they are serious.
Changing loops, breaking loops.
Some of these changes are to
their prime directives, Bernard.
They could lie to us, maybe
even hurt us or the guests.
- Who issued the modifications?
- I don't know.
The best I can tell? Uh...
- Arnold.
- He's dead.
Yeah, well, he's a pretty fucking
prolific coder for a dead guy.
Whatever argument
he was having with Ford,
it doesn't seem like he
was done making his point.
I'm gonna transfer all the
data and bring it to you.
You need to see this.
- I'll be in my office.
- Okay.
I don't want you to worry
about Jock. I'll fix him.
But I need you to tell
me what happened to it.
It saw a rabbit and it
ran. I found it like that.
Analysis.
Are you lying to me, boy?
Yes.
Tell me what really
happened to it.
I killed it.
Why?
I don't know.
That's not good enough, Robert.
Tell me what happened.
It caught the
rabbit and killed it,
and then
someone told me to
put it out of its misery.
Who told you?
A voice.
Whose voice?
Arnold.
He told me it was a
killer, but it wasn't its fault.
It was made that way.
And I could help it.
"Help it"?
If it was dead, it couldn't
hurt anything anymore.
What the fuck?
Oh, shit.
Hello?
Bernard?
Arnold?
I'm in.
You're up.
Loyalty.
Mine's been taken advantage
of, wouldn't you say?
Let's lower that a tad.
And pain.
I'd prefer it sting less next
time I want one of these chats.
Wait. What does this mean?
Some of her attributes
have already been changed.
- Paranoia, self-preservation...
- Fuck!
Someone's already been
altering her in an unlogged session.
Someone with a fuck-ton
more privileges than us.
What does that mean?
Don't know what it
means for you, sweetheart,
but I know what it means for me.
I am done with this.
So, you're done with
your little side income?
Probably your job, too.
Seeing as you have
ambitions in my line of work,
let me tell you what
I tell my new girls.
Never start something
you're not willing to finish.
And if you're getting
fucked either way,
go with the lucrative
version, sweetheart.
Now, last but not
least, what was it?
Bulk apperception?
Let's take that all the
way to the top, please.
Dear boys, we're going to
have some fun, aren't we?
English -SDH