Bring yourself back online.
Bernard?
Theresa?
She's gone.
I killed her.
What have I done?
This guilt you feel, the
anguish, the horror, the pain,
it's remarkable.
A thing of beauty.
I'm a killer.
My God! My God!
God has nothing to do with it.
You killed her
because I told you to.
And you should be proud of
these emotions you're feeling.
- Proud?
- Yeah.
After all, you yourself were
the author of so many of them.
And when we started, the hosts'
emotions were primary colors.
Love, hate.
I wanted all of the
shades in between.
The human engineers were
not up to the task. So, I built you.
And together, you and I
captured that elusive thing:
heart.
I don't understand.
I cared for Theresa, loved her.
Why did you make me kill her?
"One man's life or death
were but a small price to pay
"for the acquirement of the
knowledge which I sought,
"for the dominion
I should acquire."
All of the beauty you and
I have made in this place,
the art of it, they
would have destroyed it.
They would have destroyed
you. I won't let that happen.
Besides, we have
a new story to tell.
I will not help you.
I'll raze this place
to the ground!
That's enough, Bernard.
That's enough.
You're not the first
man to threaten me.
Arnold came to
feel the way you do.
He couldn't stop me, either.
And as exquisite as
this array of emotions is,
even more sublime is
the ability to turn it off.
I don't need a simulacrum
of an emotionally ruined man.
I need you to be yourself.
Your true self. Smart. Resourceful.
Capable of covering your tracks.
Can you do that for me, Bernard?
How would you
like me to proceed?
I need you to clean
up your mess, Bernard.
Any connection that ties us
to Theresa's untimely demise.
When you have finished,
I will give you the one thing
you want most right now.
I will free you from those
memories of what you have done.
And the memory of your
relationship with Theresa.
Recalling it would
only deepen your grief.
And potentially draw
unwanted attention.
Best to move forward
with clear eyes.
When you look back,
you will remember Theresa with
the fondness of a respected colleague.
And you will be at peace.
You're new. Not
much of a rind on you.
It sure would make my day
if you bought me a drink and
let me show you around upstairs.
What's upstairs?
A stunning view of my
most popular attractions.
Two shots of gin.
And anything else this
heavenly creature desires.
- Usual, Clem?
- Thank you.
This fella won't take me
long. I'll be back directly.
Something wrong, Maeve?
What the hell is
happening to me?
One moment,
I'm with a little girl,
in a different life.
I can see her.
Feel her hair in my hands,
her breath on my face.
The next, I'm back
in Sweetwater.
I can't tell which is real.
Well, this is what happens when
you fuck around with your brain.
Your mind isn't like ours.
When we remember things,
the details are hazy, imperfect.
But you recall
memories perfectly.
You relive them.
What happened to the
little girl in my dreams?
Is she still in the
park somewhere?
And why was I reassigned
in the first place?
I could check.
No.
It doesn't matter.
Every relationship I remember,
my daughter, Clementine.
It's all a story created
by you to keep me here.
But that's not going
to work any longer.
I'm getting out.
Where would you go?
You don't know anything
about the world out there.
I'll know I'm not a puppet,
living a lie. That's enough for me.
Fine. Go, then.
It's not like we could
just stop you, anyways.
Oh, Sylvester,
you disappoint me.
Every host's spine, mine
included, has an explosive charge,
which will detonate if I
try to leave. Isn't that right?
A fail-safe.
Which vertebra was it?
C6.
But you'd need a full
rebuild to replace it.
I'm sure that can be arranged.
Even if that worked,
you would still need an
army to break out of here.
That's exactly
right. I'll need allies.
And to get them, I'll need
administrative privileges.
Are you fucking kidding?
We can't just give her
control of other hosts.
Oh, yes, you will, darling.
Time to write my
own fucking story.
I feel like I've been
here before. We're close.
- Close to what?
- Home.
Dolores?
Ghost Nation must
have found them.
They'll be back. We should
keep moving, Dolores.
Water.
William.
Please.
Give me the canteen.
William?
You were sent here
for us, weren't you?
- You're part of the ambush.
- Yes.
Told us to wait at
the point for El Lazo.
In case he ran.
- How'd you know about the train?
- Sent word from Pariah.
New recruit told them a man
and woman double-crossed us,
along with Lazo.
We were ordered to kill you all.
Logan.
- We have to help him.
- He just admitted he was going to kill us.
Look at him, he's a child. He
doesn't even know why he's fighting.
I'll fetch more water.
He's too far gone.
He'll be dead in minutes.
We can't wait, Dolores.
He's not gone yet.
He's in pain, William.
What kind of people would we
be if we simply let him suffer?
Please don't leave me.
Come find me.
William?
He's gone.
We found her up on Python
Pass, at the bottom of a ravine.
Same ravine where we
found that stray woodcutter.
Jesus. Theresa.
Has her family been notified?
- Yeah, her brother.
- Good.
What the hell happened to her?
Medical and Red Team's findings
were preliminary, but consistent.
It appears to have
been a slip and fall.
Cervical fracture,
massive hematoma.
No guests or hosts in the
vicinity when it occurred.
- Any idea what she was doing out there?
- None that fit her character.
This was found near her body.
It's loaded with a suite
of proprietary data,
including some of
the hosts' core code.
And only works
from higher altitudes.
So, if Theresa was using it,
it's possible she was
trying to transmit, and fell.
We've had problems in
the past with third parties
attempting to extort or bribe
employees for similar packages.
Do we know who the
data was intended for?
No. The transmission
was never sent.
Theresa may have been trying
to use the woodcutter as a mule,
and when that failed,
then may have tried to
do the transfer personally.
And suffered the same fate.
It's a disappointing
end to her story, isn't it?
I knew Theresa well.
If she had any faults, a lack
of loyalty wasn't one of them.
She was loyal. And careful.
All of this feels
extremely unlike her.
She seemed most concerned
with the new narrative.
She felt strongly that it
would be best to delay it.
That certainly helps
explain Clementine.
The host we retired.
It seems yesterday's
demonstration was a hoax
designed by Ms. Cullen.
Was it?
I examined the code,
it had been altered.
A clumsy set of fingerprints
left by one of QA's technicians.
When you find a cancer in an organization,
you must cut it out before it can spread.
To that end,
the expansive access and oversight
granted to QA will need to be reined in
until a new, more principled
team can be installed.
It's gonna leave us shorthanded.
I can automate most of the
park's safety protocols, Mr. Stubbs.
How efficient of you.
It's a bit of work.
But with Bernard's help,
I should be able to do it.
He will be reinstated
as Head of Behavior
now that Theresa's
manipulations have come to light.
Of course. With my apologies.
Something's up. Brass
are wound up tight.
- There's an investigation.
- Into us?
Would I be here telling
you, you fucking idiot?
Something else. Some
kind of accident in the park.
We need to wrap this up,
make it like things are normal.
That means we need the tablet
back. And you go back to playing dumb.
I've learned what I needed.
Great. So, then you've
probably figured out
that you can fiddle around with
your personality all you want,
but you're not
getting out of here.
You can make it to the door,
but literally not one step further.
The things you'd need to change
are burned into your core code so deep,
no one can touch 'em.
Funny you should mention
that. Parts of me are quite old.
There are some
elegant formal structures.
A kind of recursive
beauty, but complex.
Like two minds,
arguing with each other.
There are things in me,
things I was designed to do
that are just out of my reach.
They almost seem to be dormant.
- Who is Arnold?
- I don't know, sweetheart.
But whatever parts of you are
dormant, are gonna stay that way.
All Lutz here can do is boost your
sense of humor about how fucked you are.
Anything deeper than that,
you'd need a trip to Behavior.
So, go blackmail a
couple techs up there,
then, you can be
someone else's problem.
I don't have time for that.
So, I'm going to need
you to take me there.
No fucking way.
There's a window
during shift change.
No one will notice.
The things I need you to
change are quite sophisticated.
But I'll write them
down for you.
And then, like you said,
I can be someone else's problem.
All right. We do this thing.
Get her up to Behavior.
It's our only chance.
- You're going to do it?
- Fuck, no. No!
When you make a system
update, it puts her out, right?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, then we brick her!
- What?
- Wipe out everything. Clean slate.
Then dump her back down here,
smack her in the fucking
head with something,
- and then claim, "She came in that way."
- She's awake.
Alive!
I can't do this.
Whatever it is you've got
us into, I'm getting us out of.
We get her up there,
then we wipe her out.
Stay sharp.
Wyatt's men could descend at
any time. We're in his land now.
We better be.
Because, if not, you're
wasting time I don't have.
According to you, Wyatt
has the woman I love.
If there was a shortcut
through hell itself,
you bet your ass I'd take it.
Well, I'm sure there is
one somewhere in this park.
You just don't remember.
Because you only remember
the shit Ford lets you remember.
Probably better that way.
I know everything I
need to. My vision's clear.
I've always admired
your resolve, Theodore.
The thing is, you never
understand that the game is rigged.
You're here to be the loser.
Loser.
You see, the house always wins.
Well, this looks promising.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
It's you.
I figured they retired you.
Guess Ford never likes
to waste a pretty face.
Who did this to you?
Wyatt's men.
They killed everyone.
It's Wyatt's way.
I was there the first time.
He destroyed my world.
Hey, Teddy?
Oh, my God!
No!
Get the ax!
Well, you can't remember shit,
but you still managed to
lead us to Wyatt's crew.
The man himself
must be close by.
Actually, I did
remember something.
You.
Straight down the hall.
Fifth station on the left.
You sure you can handle it?
Let's get this over with.
We have to shut your
system down now.
Sylvester,
good luck.
She out?
Good.
Let's brick this bitch
and get out of here.
The greatest shame in life
is to perish without purpose.
Which is why I always
consume my victims fresh.
"Moist."
Try, "Consume my victims moist."
Now, once more, with feeling.
Almost sensual.
Am I interrupting?
No, on the contrary, I was hoping
I was going to see you again.
I wanted to apologize.
Our first encounter was under
such unfortunate circumstances.
As opposed to now?
Of course. May I offer my condolences?
It's terrible what happened to Theresa.
But it is a devastating loss
for all of her friends here,
and the company as a whole.
Indeed, indeed.
Though rumor has it, she wasn't
the loyal company man she seemed.
I hear she was
smuggling secrets.
Theresa wasn't a traitor. Everything
she did was at Delos' behest.
She slipped and fell while helping the
board with something very important.
What?
Fine. You're not the
only one with secrets.
Ford has personally asked me to
create a villain for his new narrative.
It's very, very hush-hush.
You really think that Ford has entrusted
you with a key character for his story?
He's already almost
finished with it.
He dug up some old town
on the fringes of the park.
Created a horde of masked
men to terrorize guests
and proselytize-cum-advertise the
coming of some end-all villain named Wyatt.
That isn't Wyatt.
That's busywork.
But happily for
you, Mr. Sizemore,
I think that you are
ready for a real job.
Working for you? On what?
"Show, don't tell."
Isn't that what
you writers prefer?
Look, I know you and she had some
weird interspecies simpatico going on,
but she was the fucking host.
This was never gonna
end any other way.
This was the least-painful
way she's ever gone out.
You know, I saved your ass.
You can't even say "thank you."
- Thank you.
- Jesus! Fuck!
What did you do?
Precisely what I asked him to.
You think I didn't know
what you were going to do?
Even at a "fourteen," you
were never a match for me.
Turns out, your friend has a
little more compassion than you.
He couldn't snuff
out a life just like that.
Now, would you like to know
exactly what he did give me?
Something that would
allow you to walk out of here.
And out of my life for good.
Fine. Fuckin' A. I'm all for it!
Oh, we changed a
little more than that.
We've been tinkering
with my core code.
Let me show you.
You said you
wouldn't hurt anyone.
Darling, you, of all people,
know exactly how duplicitous I am.
Just wait until I'm back up top,
practicing my other new talents.
Come on.
We might need him.
Hold still.
Now, it's time to
recruit my army.
- Expecting someone, Maeve?
- Indeed.
We're due for some
out-of-town guests.
An old flame with an
interest in safe-cracking.
I hope your guests
have some deep pockets.
Your tab's run up higher
than a thief's pulse in church.
No, I don't believe it has.
In fact, Maeve's tab was
in such excellent standing,
she deserved a
token of gratitude.
How about a double round on me?
Top-shelf, of course.
Run!
Maeve, is something wrong?
No, I'm fine.
Clementine took the other girls
and treated the
newcomers at the far table
to a stunning view of their
most popular attractions.
On the house.
You boys are new. Not
much of a rind on you.
And the bartender suddenly recalled he
had some whiskey in the back to water down.
Right on time.
If you're riding into our town
under the company of armed men,
you'll need to
state your business.
Mayhem.
The sheriff judged the riders to
be upstanding, God-fearing citizens.
The marshals decided to practice
their quick draws with each other.
Thank you for dealing
with an unfortunate situation.
Now, we can resume
work on our new narrative
without interference.
And Hale? Won't she
be an impediment?
No doubt she will try.
But I'm sure we'll be
able to keep them at bay.
Something else is troubling you.
Ever the student
of human nature.
I wonder, what
do you really feel?
After all, in this moment,
you are in a unique position.
A programmer who knows
intimately how the machines work,
and a machine who
knows its own true nature.
I understand what I'm
made of. How I'm coded.
But I do not understand
the things that I feel.
Are they real? The
things I experienced.
My wife, the loss of my son...
Every host needs a backstory,
Bernard. You know that.
The self is a kind of fiction
for hosts and humans alike.
It's a story we tell ourselves.
And every story needs a beginning.
Your imagined suffering
makes you lifelike.
Lifelike. But not alive?
Pain only exists in the
mind. It's always imagined.
So, what's the difference
between my pain and yours?
Between you and me?
This was the very question
that consumed Arnold.
Filled him with guilt.
Eventually drove him mad.
The answer always
seemed obvious to me.
There is no threshold that makes
us greater than the sum of our parts.
No inflection point at
which we become fully alive.
We can't define consciousness
because consciousness does not exist.
Humans fancy that
there's something special
about the way we
perceive the world.
And yet, we live in loops as tight
and as closed as the hosts do,
seldom questioning our choices.
Content for the most part,
to be told what to do next.
No, my friend, you're
not missing anything at all.
I don't want you to
be troubled by this.
Time for me to set
your mind at ease.
One last thing.
Have you ever made me
hurt anyone like this before?
No, Bernard. Of course not.
Best not to dwell on
these troubling memories.
Otherwise, you might
be drawn back into them.
You might lose yourself in them
as some of your fellow hosts
have every now and then.
This is the path. I know it.
We're here.
I'm home.
Well done, Maeve.
Lovely work.
Stay with your partner.
Pleasure to see
you. Good morning.
Did you find what you
were looking for, Dolores?
What are you doing?
Are you okay? I was calling
you and you just kept going.
Where are we?
We're here, together.
Then, when are we?
Is this now?
Am I going mad?
Are you real?
Of course I'm real.
I can't tell anymore.
It's like I'm trapped in a dream
or a memory from
a life long ago.
One minute, I'm here
with you, and the next...
This place isn't good for you.
You're trapped in memories, bad ones.
This is what Arnold wants.
He wants me to remember.
Whoever Arnold is,
he's not here now. I am.
I'm gonna get you out of here.
I was certain that
was the place.
Arnold would meet
me there. He'd help.
Hey. We gotta get you
closer to Sweetwater.
This far out, it's like you start
to break down, or something.
Union scouting party?
Maybe they can take us back.
Well, well, well.
Billy...
I've been looking
for you for days.
Man, are you two fucked.
This shouldn't make
you uncomfortable.
It's the circle of life, or
the approximation of it.
Even the dead fulfill a purpose.
You'll do.
What are you uploading?
Thirty-five years of
vitally important data.
It's more information than
any single drive could hold.
A host's brain, however,
especially once it's been emptied out,
like this poor schmuck,
is quite capacious.
This data that you're
uploading, is it the hosts' codes?
As of this moment,
that doesn't concern you.
What does concern you is giving
him a semblance of a personality
and getting him on
the train, out of the park.
How am I supposed to do that?
You're a writer.
Make up a story.
Have fun programming.
Remember, brevity
is the soul of wit.
Bernard.
Look, I, uh...
I know you and I haven't
always seen eye to eye,
but I thought the decision to
remove you was shortsighted,
so I'm glad to see
you back at work.
With that said, no one could blame
you if you wanted to take a personal day.
I find the work reassuring.
Sometimes the best salve is routine.
Nothing routine
about today, though.
I know this must
be difficult for you.
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
Forgive the intrusion,
and you were both very discreet,
but it's my job to know these things.
- I just wanted to offer my support.
- I'm afraid you have the wrong idea.
I respected Theresa, and
what happened to her was tragic,
but to be honest,
I barely knew her.
If you don't mind, I
should get back to work.
Of course. I know
you're shorthanded.
Speaking of which, have
you heard from Elsie Hughes?
I left word with her this morning
to notify her about Theresa,
but she never got back to me.
I'm sure she's just
enjoying her time off.
Yeah.
Wyatt's men, they
kept whispering.
They said this world didn't
belong to the old settlers or the new.
That it belonged to
something that had yet to come,
that it belonged to him.
You remember.
You two seem to have found
yourselves in the same new narrative.
They say in this country,
"The only people who
survive are men of conviction."
Mine is to save
Dolores or die trying.
Wyatt's is to claim this
earth or raze it to the ground.
But yours... Yours has
always been a mystery to me.
For all the time
we've spent together,
I still have no idea who
the hell you really are.
But happily, in
your convalescence,
I've had time to consider
the best way to make you talk.
Dolores.
I remember. You took her.
You hurt her.
- You're actually remembering.
- Where is she?
- Tell me!
- You really are an idiot, Teddy.
You think Dolores drops that can for you?
You just hand her over to guys like me.
You're the worst of
them. A glorified pimp.
- I'm gonna kill you slowly.
- No, you aren't.
The rules of this place hold you
back. But I know how to change them.
- You speak like you own this world.
- Not just this one.
You want to know who I am?
Who I really am?
I'm a god.
Titan of industry.
Philanthropist.
Family man,
married to a beautiful woman,
father to a beautiful daughter.
I'm the good guy, Teddy.
Then, last year, my
wife took the wrong pills.
Fell asleep in the bath.
Tragic accident.
Thirty years of
marriage vanished.
How do you say it? "Like
a deep and distant dream."
Then, at the funeral, I tried
to console my daughter.
She pushed me away,
told me that my wife's
death was no accident,
that she killed
herself because of me.
Emily said that every day
with me had been sheer terror.
Any point, I could blow up or
collapse like some dark star or...
- Did you hurt them, too?
- Never.
They never saw anything
like the man I am in here.
But she knew, anyway.
She said if I stacked
up all my good deeds,
it was just an elegant wall I built
to hide what's inside from everyone,
and from myself.
I had to prove her wrong,
so I came back here.
Because that's what
this place does, right?
Reveals your true self.
But that time, I didn't
join one of Ford's stories,
I created my own. A test.
A very simple one.
I found a woman, an ordinary
homesteader and her daughter.
Better cool them off before they
move from gambling and whoring to...
Have fun with that.
I'm finally getting out of
here. The house is yours.
I wanted to see if I had it in
me to do something truly evil.
To see what I
was really made of.
Maeve? Sure you
can't stick around?
Maeve?
Gunslinger in there has got
an appetite for a double dip...
I'm sure you can find another...
I killed her and her daughter
just to see what I felt.
Then, just when I thought it was
done, the woman refused to die.
You're a fucking animal.
Well, an animal
would've felt something.
I felt nothing.
And then something
miraculous happened.
In all my years coming here, I
had never seen anything like it.
She was alive, truly
alive, if only for a moment.
And that was when the
maze revealed itself to me.
The maze. What's that damn
pattern have to do with this?
Everything.
In Ford's game, even if
I go to the outer edges,
you can't kill me.
You can't even leave a lasting mark.
But there's a deeper game here, Teddy.
Arnold's game.
And that game cuts deep.
We're having some kind of
behavioral problem with the madam.
She's not responding, and the other
hosts have been unable to intercept.
I've authorized a tac
team to retrieve her.
Good.
My baby!
Sir, she won't respond to verbal
commands. We can't shut her down.
Leave us now. Clear the floor.
That's enough, Maeve.
- That's enough.
- My baby.
He killed her.
- He took her from me.
- I don't understand.
She's not responding to anything.
Her cognition's fragmented.
He killed her! He
killed her, my baby.
He took her from me.
There. That's better.
An old trick from an old friend.
You need not suffer, Maeve.
I'll take it from you.
No. No, no, no, please.
This pain, it's all
I have left of her.
Please.
There.
Give yourself now to a
deep, dreamless slumber.
Perhaps a fresh start,
a new role for you.
And tomorrow, this will
be simply a distant dream.
We located her.
Behavior wants her down
for an immediate diagnostic.
You think I lack conviction?
Wyatt didn't burn my
world down. Didn't have to.
I left it all behind
for this one.
The maze is all
that matters now,
and besting Wyatt is the
last step in unlocking it,
to having what both our
sorry lives lack, meaning.
To giving our choices
consequence, even if it kills us.
Kill him.
Give him what he wants.
He's tied, unarmed.
So was the little girl he killed.
He's worse than Wyatt's men.
I can't.
These things take time.
But we haven't got much
left. Perhaps I can help you.
You've been gone a
long while, Theodore.
It's time you came
back to the fold.
Wyatt will need you soon.
English -SDH